<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<section xml:id="section-communication">
  <title>Communication</title>
  <paragraphs>
    <title>Contact Your Instructor</title>
    <p>
      The best way to contact me is by using the D2L Brightspace email system from the D2L Connect,
      Classlist tool. You can use it to send an email to me or your classmates.
    </p>
    <p>
      Please include a relevant subject in the header of your email. The subject should include the
      class you are taking and the topic of your message. For example, you email subject line might
      be:
      <cd>[MTH 95]: Help with Section 10.1 Homework</cd>
      Writing an email subject this way helps me get back to you quickly. Sometimes I get a hundred
      emails in just one day, and I want your emails to stand out.
    </p>
    <p>
      If your question/comment would be of interest to other students, please consider posting it
      to the <q>Ask a Question</q> Discussions area instead. Then I can publicly answer your
      question, and the entire class might benefit.
    </p>
    <p>
      We can also meet over Zoom to talk through anything you' like to talk about.
    </p>
  </paragraphs>
  <paragraphs>
    <title>Responses from Your Instructor</title>
    <p>
      I will reply to your emails and discussion posts within 48 hours, and often much
      sooner. If you send me a message in the evening, it's more likely that I won't reply until the
      following day. Please don't wait until the evening an assignment is due to reach out to me for
      help, or else I might not be able to reply until it is too late.
    </p>
  </paragraphs>
  <paragraphs>
    <title>Discord</title>
    <p>
      This course has a Discord server, and I recommend that you join. If you have never used
      Discord before, what matters is that I think it is a great way for you (as an online student)
      to form connections with other students in the class. You are not required to join Discord,
      but please give it a try. You should receive an invitation from me over email. That invitation
      eventually expires, so if you waited too long, just send me a message so I can send you a new
      invitation.
    </p>
  </paragraphs>
</section>
