<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<section xml:id="section-communication">
  <title>Communication</title>
  <paragraphs>
    <title>Best Way to Contact Me</title>
    <p>
      The best way to contact me is by using the D2L Brightspace e-mail system which can be accessed
      from the Classlist. You can use it to send an e-mail to me and/or your classmates.
    </p>
    <p>
      You should include a relevant subject in the <q>Subject:</q> header of your e-mail. The
      subject should include the class you are taking (including the course number and CRN) and the
      topic of your message. For example, you email subject line might be:
      <cd>[MTH 95 - CRN 42651]: Help with Section 10.1 Homework</cd>
      If you treat your email subject line this way, it helps me prioritize getting back to you
      quickly. I sometimes get a hundred or more emails in just one day, and I want your emails (my
      student's emails) to be the ones I prioritize.
    </p>
    <p>
      If your question or comment would be of interest to other students, please consider posting it
      to the General Discussions area instead. Then I can publicly answer your question, and the
      entire class will benefit from the answers.
    </p>
    <p>
      You can also find me in Office Hours as described in <xref ref="section-contact-info"/>.
    </p>
  </paragraphs>
  <paragraphs>
    <title>Responses from Me</title>
    <p>
      You can expect me to reply to your emails and discussion posts within 48 hours, and often much
      sooner. I often will not reply to messages sent in the evening until the following day. This
      is only because I am not always online in the evenings. This means that if you wait until the
      evening an assignment is due to reach out to me for help, then I might not get to replying
      until after the assignment is due.
    </p>
  </paragraphs>
  <paragraphs>
    <title>Discord</title>
    <p>
      This course has an associated Discord server, and I recommend that you join. If you have never
      used Discord before, I think that you will find it very helpful for this course. You should
      receive an invitation from me over email. That invitation eventually expires, so if you waited
      too long, just send me a message so I can send you a new inivitation.
    </p>
    <p>
      Discord will be great for you communicating with each other within your study groups. But you
      can also use it to communicate with the entire class or with me.
    </p>
  </paragraphs>
</section>
