<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!-- This file is part of Alex Jordan's syllabus -->

<section xml:id="section-contact-info">
  <title>Contact Information</title>
  <p>
    To reach me or PCC:
  </p>
  <sidebyside margins="0% 0%" valign="middle">
    <p>
      <dl width="narrow">
        <li>
          <title>Instructor</title>
          <p>Alex Jordan</p>
        </li>
        <li>
          <title>Office</title>
          <p>CA SSB 317</p>
        </li>
        <li>
          <title>Phone</title>
          <p>971-722-4138<fn>Not a good way to reach me.</fn></p>
        </li>
        <li>
          <title>Email</title>
          <p><email>alex.jordan@pcc.edu</email></p>
        </li>
      </dl>
    </p>
    <tabular>
      <row>
        <cell>Portland Community College</cell>
      </row>
      <row>
        <cell>Cascade Campus</cell>
      </row>
      <row>
        <cell>705 N Killingsworth St.</cell>
      </row>
      <row>
        <cell>Portland, OR 97217</cell>
      </row>
    </tabular>
  </sidebyside>
  <p>
    Because of federal privacy laws, all email communications related to this class need to be sent
    to and from your <c>@pcc.edu</c> email address, or using D2L's Classlist messaging tool.
  </p>
  <tabular top="major" valign="top" left="major" bottom="minor">
    <col/>
    <col/>
    <col right="major"/>
    <col right="major"/>
    <col right="major"/>
    <row bottom="medium">
      <cell>CRN</cell>
      <cell>Days/Time</cell>
      <cell>Place</cell>
      <cell>Midterm Exam</cell>
      <cell>Final Exam</cell>
    </row>
    <row bottom="major">
      <cell>
        <line>11842</line>
        <line>14956</line>
      </cell>
      <cell>async</cell>
      <cell>
        <line>D2L</line>
        <line>Zoom</line>
        <line>Discord</line>
        <line>etc.</line>
      </cell>
      <cell>
        <line>Thursday Feb 5</line>
        <line>CRN 11842: 9:00<ndash/>11:30</line>
        <line>CRN 14956: 1:00<ndash/>3:30</line>
        <line>(can ask to switch)</line>
      </cell>
      <cell>
        <line>Tuesday Mar 17</line>
        <line>CRN 11842: 9:00<ndash/>11:30</line>
        <line>CRN 14956: 1:00<ndash/>3:30</line>
        <line>(can ask to switch)</line>
      </cell>
    </row>
  </tabular>
  <p>
    The two exams are proctored. We will use <q>remote proctoring</q> where you take the exam from
    home (or wherever) and we will use Zoom to allow me to monitor your workspace. For details, see
    <xref ref="section-exams"/>. The most important thing for now is to plan to be somewhere on the
    exam dates that is quiet and comfortable, with a strong internet connection on a device that has
    Zoom installed. You might need <em>two</em> devices. You always need a computer or laptop
    (<em>not</em> a tablet). Additionally you need a device with a camera that will cover your work
    area. This camera can <em>not</em> be embedded in a laptop screen. Most often, students either
    use a detachable webcam or they use a phone/tablet for a second connection to Zoom.
  </p>
  <p>
    It is possible to take your exams in-person, or proctored remotely at an alternate time. But
    these arrangements need to be made at least one week in advance. See <xref ref="section-exams"/>
    for details.
  </p>
  <p>
    I will meet with you over Zoom as needed, and frequently invite you to meet with me that way. If
    you are struggling with any topics from the course, completing assignments, or studying for the
    exams, let's meet over Zoom and talk about it.
  </p>
</section>
