<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<section xml:id="section-course-description">
  <title>Course Description</title>
  <p>
    Taken from the official PCC course description:
  </p>
  <sidebyside>
    <tabular>
      <col halign="right" />
      <col/>
      <row>
        <cell>Course Number:</cell>
        <cell>MTH 95</cell>
      </row>
      <row>
        <cell>Course Title:</cell>
        <cell>Intermediate Algebra</cell>
      </row>
      <row>
        <cell>Credit Hours:</cell>
        <cell>4</cell>
      </row>
      <row>
        <cell>Lecture Hours:</cell>
        <cell>30</cell>
      </row>
      <row>
        <cell>Lecture/Lab Hours:</cell>
        <cell>20</cell>
      </row>
    </tabular>
  </sidebyside>
  <p>
    Introduces algebraic concepts and processes with a focus on factoring, functions, rational
    expressions, solving equations (quadratic, rational, radical, absolute value), and solving
    inequalities. Emphasizes number-sense, applications, graphs, formulas, and proper mathematical
    notation. Prerequisites: (MTH 63 or MTH 65 or MTH 70) and (RD 90 and WR 90) or IRW 90 or
    equivalent placement. Recommended: MTH 63 or MTH 65 or MTH 70 be taken within the past 4 terms.
    The PCC math department recommends that students take MTH courses in consecutive terms. Audit
    available.
  </p>
  <paragraphs>
    <title>Intended Outcomes for the Course</title>
    <p>
      Upon completion of the course students should be able to:
      <ol>
        <li>
          <p>
            Factor expressions and use factoring to simplify rational expressions and solve
            quadratic equations.
          </p>
        </li>
        <li>
          <p>
            Solve absolute value, quadratic, rational, radical equations, and compound inequalities
            both symbolically and graphically.
          </p>
        </li>
        <li>
          <p>
            Understand the definition of a function and use it to distinguish between function and
            non-function relationships.
          </p>
        </li>
        <li>
          <p>
            Interpret information provided in function notation given a function expressed in
            graphical, symbolic, numeric, or verbal form.
          </p>
        </li>
        <li>
          <p>
            Use variables to represent unknown quantities, create a function to model a situation,
            and use algebra and/or technology to find and interpret a result.
          </p>
        </li>
        <li>
          <p>
            Interpret properties of functions and relations, such as the meaning of ordered pairs,
            domain and range, maximum and minimum values, and intercepts.
          </p>
        </li>
      </ol>
    </p>
  </paragraphs>
  <p>
    The complete Course Content and Outcome Guide can be found at
    <url href="https://www.pcc.edu/ccog/" visual="www.pcc.edu/ccog">www.pcc.edu/ccog/</url>.
  </p>
</section>
