<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<section xml:id="section-exams">
  <title>Exams</title>
  <p>
    While this is an online course without scheduled class meetings, nevertheless there are required
    proctored exam sessions. Most students will participate in <q>remote proctoring</q> where you
    take the exams from home (or wherever). But you will have a video feed (that only I can see)
    that shows your work area. And you will be screen sharing on Zoom (again, only I will see this).
    The days and times are:
    <dl width="narrow">
      <li>
        <title>Midterm Exam</title>
        <p>
          Tuesday 7/25 for CRN 33419, and Wednesday 7/26 for CRN 31183.
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <title>Final Exam</title>
        <p>
          Tuesday 8/29 for CRN 33419, and Wednesday 8/30 for CRN 31183.
        </p>
      </li>
    </dl>
    The exams officially run from 2:00<ndash/>4:20. However you need to arrive early for a check-in
    procedure where we make sure your work area is acceptable and you have the technology issues
    ironed out. The check-in procedure includes showing a photo ID (PCC student ID card, driver's
    license, passport, military ID, <ellipsis/>) to confirm your identity while taking these exams.
    <alert>Plan to arrive in the Zoom session at 1:30 for the check-in procedure.</alert>
  </p>
  <p>
    You might be offered the chance to take the exam in the other CRN's time slot. Reach out to me
    if you need this. I have to make sure that I do not have too many students in any one of the two
    sessions.
  </p>
  <p>
    These sessions are almost 2.5 hours long. However you may need less time than that. Some
    students complete these exams in under an hour.
  </p>
  <paragraphs>
    <title>What is <q>virtual proctoring</q>?</title>
    <p>
      Please take some time to read the
      <url href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1Oab3ck-3foDHfLTwfFuC5pkTpziXz9KHpIy1i_RFxuA" visual="docs.google.com/document/d/1Oab3ck-3foDHfLTwfFuC5pkTpziXz9KHpIy1i_RFxuA">Student Guide to Virtually Proctored Exams in Zoom</url>.
      This explains in writing what a <q>virtually proctored</q> exam will be like better than I can
      here.
    </p>
    <p>
      We will practice the setup for a virtually proctored exam ahead of time. I will arrange for a
      session when many of us can practice. For others, we can meet individually or in smaller
      groups over Zoom to practice.
    </p>
  </paragraphs>
  <paragraphs>
    <title>Alternatives</title>
    <p>
      If you cannot participate in the <q>remote proctored</q> exams as described above (maybe you
      do not meet the technology requirements, have an unavoidable scheduling conflict, or just
      prefer to take exams in person) there are some alternatives. However, please note that there
      are no exceptions to having to take the exams with a proctor. If you need to explore the
      alternatives below, please contact me as soon as possible to begin discussing your options.
      The alternatives include:
      <ul>
        <li>
          <p>
            You identify a proctoring institution (such as another college) that is closer to where
            you live. You will be responsible for making proctoring appointments with them two weeks
            in advance of the exam dates. I will provide you with a form<fn>This form is linked from
            our D2L course at the bottom of the Content menu.</fn> that you complete with the
            assistance of that institution's testing center. You may take an exam a few days earlier
            than the dates listed above, but not later.
          </p>
        </li>
        <li>
          <p>
            You have an AEDR accommodation for extended time or a private working area. Then you
            will work with PCC AEDR two weeks in advance to schedule appointments for these exams.
            These might be in-person or remotely proctored, as is appropriate for your needs. You
            may take an exam a few days earlier than the dates listed above, but not later.
          </p>
        </li>
        <li>
          <p>
            If you have a scheduling conflict, you can make an appointment with a PCC testing center
            for a virtually proctored exam. Email <email>testing.remote@pcc.edu</email> to arrange
            an appointment. Once it is scheduled, <alert>contact me to tell me about your
            appointment.</alert>
          </p>
        </li>
        <li>
          <p>
            If you simply prefer to take your exams in person, you can make an appointment with a
            PCC testing center for an in-person proctored exam. Email
            <email>testing.remote@pcc.edu</email> to arrange an appointment. Once it is scheduled,
            <alert>contact me to tell me about your appointment.</alert>
          </p>
        </li>
      </ul>
      You may contact me if you have some situation that is not covered here and you would like to ask about it.
    </p>
  </paragraphs>
  <p>
    By registering for this course, you agree to all of the above. By default, you will take an exam
    using remote proctoring over Zoom at the scheduled time. Or you will plan at least two weeks in
    advance for one of the alternative arrangements.
  </p>
  <p>
    The midterm exam and the final exam will each be worth 24% of your final grade.
  </p>
</section>
