<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<section xml:id="section-exams">
  <title>Exams</title>
  <p>
    This is an online course without scheduled class meetings, but there are still <alert>required
    proctored exams</alert>. Most students will participate in <q>remote proctoring</q> where you
    take the exams from home (or wherever). But you will have a video feed (that only I can see)
    that shows your work area. And you will be screen sharing on Zoom (again, only I will see this).
    The days and times are:
    <dl width="narrow">
      <li>
        <title>Midterm Exam</title>
        <p>
          CRN 11842: Thursday 2/5 9:00<ndash/>12:00
        </p>
        <p>
          CRN 14956: Thursday 2/5 1:00<ndash/>4:00
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <title>Final Exam</title>
        <p>
          CRN 11842: Tuesday 3/17 9:00<ndash/>12:00
        </p>
        <p>
          CRN 14956: Tuesday 3/17 1:00<ndash/>4:00
        </p>
      </li>
    </dl>
    Check these times against your work/school/travel schedule immediately. If you'd like to trade
    your time slot, let me know. It's probably OK, I just have to make sure that not too many
    students take a remote procotred exam at the same time.
    See below if you need to make alternative arrangements.
  </p>
  <p>
    The first 30 minutes is for a check-in procedure where we make sure your work area is acceptable
    and you have the technology issues ironed out. The check-in procedure includes showing a photo
    ID (PCC student ID card, driver's license, passport, military ID, <ellipsis/>) to confirm your
    identity while taking these exams.
  </p>
  <p>
    The actual time you have for working on each exam is almost 2 hours long. However you may need
    less time than that. Some students complete these exams in under an hour.
  </p>
  <paragraphs>
    <title>What is <q>virtual proctoring</q>?</title>
    <p>
      Please take some time to read the
      <url href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1Oab3ck-3foDHfLTwfFuC5pkTpziXz9KHpIy1i_RFxuA" visual="docs.google.com/document/d/1Oab3ck-3foDHfLTwfFuC5pkTpziXz9KHpIy1i_RFxuA">Student Guide to Virtually Proctored Exams in Zoom</url>.
      This explains what a <q>virtually proctored</q> exam is like better than I can.
    </p>
    <p>
      We will practice the setup for a virtually proctored exam ahead of time. I will arrange for a
      session when many of us can practice. For others, we can meet individually or in smaller
      groups over Zoom to practice.
    </p>
  </paragraphs>
  <paragraphs>
    <title>Alternatives</title>
    <p>
      If you cannot participate in the <q>remote proctored</q> exams as described above (maybe you
      do not meet the technology requirements, have an unavoidable scheduling conflict, or just
      prefer to take exams in person) there are some alternatives. However, please note that there
      are no exceptions to having to take the exams with a proctor. If you need to explore the
      alternatives below, please contact me as soon as possible to begin discussing your options.
      The alternatives include:
      <ul>
        <li>
          <p>
            You identify a proctoring institution (such as another college) that is closer to where
            you live. You will be responsible for making proctoring appointments with them two weeks
            in advance of the exam dates. I will provide you with a form<fn>This form is linked from
            our D2L course at the bottom of the Content menu.</fn> that you complete with the
            assistance of that institution's testing center. <alert>Then someone from that
            institution must email me the form directly.</alert> This is why we are asking you to
            take care of this early. You may take an exam earlier than the dates listed above, but
            not later.
          </p>
        </li>
        <li>
          <p>
            You have an AEDR accommodation for extended time or a private working area. Then you
            will work with PCC AEDR at least one week in advance to schedule appointments for these
            exams. These might be in-person or remotely proctored, as is appropriate for your needs.
            You may take an exam earlier than the dates listed above, but not later.
          </p>
        </li>
        <li>
          <p>
            If you have a scheduling conflict or if you simply prefer to take your exams in person,
            you can make an appointment with a PCC testing center for a virtually proctored exam.
            Visit <url href="https://pcc.edu/testing" visual="pcc.edu/testing"/> (Proctored exams)
            to arrange an appointment. Once it is scheduled, <alert>contact me to tell me about your
            appointment.</alert>
          </p>
        </li>
      </ul>
      You may contact me if you have some situation that is not covered here and you would like to
      ask about it.
    </p>
  </paragraphs>
  <p>
    By registering for this course, you agree to all of the above. By default, you will take an exam
    using remote proctoring over Zoom at the scheduled time. Or you will plan at least one week in
    advance for one of the alternative arrangements.
  </p>
  <p>
    The midterm exam and the final exam will each be worth 20% of your final grade.
  </p>
</section>
