<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<section xml:id="section-expectations">
  <title>Expectations</title>
  <p>
    Failure to meet certain expectations within the first week of class will result in being marked
    as a <q>no show</q> and dropped from the class. To avoid being marked as a <q>no show</q>:
    <ul>
      <li>
        <p>
          All activities from <q>Module 0</q> must be completed by Thursday at 10:00 pm on
          the first week of class. Module 0 in D2L states the details of what is required.
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>
          Module 1 is where actual academic content for the course begins. All Module 1 assignments
          (video lecture notes, <webwork/>, and a worksheet) are due Sunday night at 10:00pm. You
          must complete at least one of these assignments by the Sunday night deadline. (Of course
          you should complete them all, but to avoid being marked <q>no show</q>, completing one is
          enough.)
        </p>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </p>
  <p>
    Students in this course are expected to enter the course several times a week. Class
    announcements are posted on our D2L course landing page, and it is your responsibility to read
    these announcements.
  </p>
  <p>
    Check your <em>pcc.edu</em> email daily. I sometimes send important information in mass emails to
    the class. It is your responsibility to read these messages as they come. Also I may be replying
    to a message that you initiated, and I am only permitted to contact you using your
    <em>pcc.edu</em> email address.
  </p>
  <p>
    If you are not going to take exams using <q>remote proctoring</q> on the official exam dates
    with the rest of the class, then you have responsibilities to make other arrangements according
    to <xref ref="section-exams"/>. These arrangements need to be in place at least one week ahead
    of the exam.
  </p>
  <p>
    Make an honest effort to collaborate with your partners on the worksheet assignments. As this is
    an asynchronous class, and everyone has different schedules and outside responsibilities, it is
    not always possible. But it can be rewarding to make connections with the handful of people in
    your group.
  </p>
  <p>
    Reach out to me or a tutor early when you are having trouble with a topic. Your responsibility
    is to recognize when you need this help. We can make a plan to help you if we have enough time.
    We might meet over Zoom or in person, whatever we need to do.
  </p>
</section>
