<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!-- This file is part of Alex Jordan's syllabus -->

<section xml:id="grades" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
    <title>Grades</title>

    <introduction>
        <p>General PCC Grading Guidelines are found at <url href="http://catalog.pcc.edu/handbook/g301-gradingguidelines/">catalog.pcc.edu/handbook/g301-gradingguidelines</url>.</p>
    </introduction>

    <paragraphs>
        <title>Attendance/Participation</title>
        <p>Each day of class that you attend is worth <quantity><mag>0.25</mag><unit base="percent"/></quantity> of your grade, up to a maximum of <quantity><mag>4</mag><unit base="percent"/></quantity>. This does not include holidays, inservice days, or days where the entire class period is devoted to an exam. Typically in a term this leaves at least one absence that would not have a direct effect on your grade. However missing class will hurt your chances for success on exams because you will not get the same attention that your classmates had.</p>
    </paragraphs>

    <paragraphs>
        <title>Web Assignments</title>
        <p>Most of your homework for this class is to be submitted online through the free program <webwork/>. For details, see <xref ref="section-webwork" text="type-global"/>. Collectively, all web assignments are worth <quantity><mag>16</mag><unit base="percent"/></quantity> of your final grade. For every web assignment that you do not submit (or have a poor score for), I will <em>replace</em> that score with the score you get on your next exam.</p>

        <p>If you write up all of the problems from a web homework on paper, you may turn that in so that I may review your math communication style and give you feedback. This is <em>not</em> a replacement for doing the web homework online. Instead, if you do this, I will add up to 10<percent /> to those web assignments. For example, suppose your <webwork/> grade for an assignment is 85<percent /> and you turn in a write-up of those problems. Suppose that I grade your write-up to be <m>9/10</m>. Then your final recorded score for the assignment will be <m>85\%+9\%=94\%</m>.</p>
    </paragraphs>

    <paragraphs>
        <title>Written Assignments</title>
        <p>Some problems will be assigned to write up and turn in. These will be exercises where part of the task is to create some kind of graph, so <webwork /> will not be able to grade you. Each written assignment is worth <quantity><mag>1</mag><unit base="percent"/></quantity> of your grade for a total of <quantity><mag>5</mag><unit base="percent"/></quantity>. See <xref ref="section-written-assignments"/> for the specifics.</p>
    </paragraphs>

    <!-- <paragraphs>
        <title>Written Assignments</title>
        <p>Selections of problems from the textbook will be assigned to be be written up formally. Each written assignment is worth <quantity><mag>1</mag><unit base="percent"/></quantity> of your grade for a total of <quantity><mag>10</mag><unit base="percent"/></quantity>. See <xref text="title" ref="section-written-assignments"/> for the specifics.</p>
    </paragraphs> -->

    <paragraphs>
        <title>Late Homework</title>
        <p>Web assignments are due whenever <webwork/> says they are due for full credit.  There is no way to get credit for a late web assignment (unless you unlock an achievement item reward). After the due date, you may still type in answers to check your work, but doing so will not increase your score. After the due date, answers are available if you re-visit the problem. Any <webwork/> score can be <em>overwritten</em> by your next exam score, if that is to your benefit.</p>

        <p>You may <em>always</em> ask me for an extension to the web homework due date, as long as you ask well <em>before</em> the due date. I cannot change the due date for you if the problem set closes first. If you need an extension, please email me to request that at least 24 hours before the regular due date.</p>

        <p>Written assignments that are received late may receive a zero. If I have already graded the stack of everyone else's papers, then it is absolutely too late. You may try to turn in something late, and if I have not yet graded everyone else's, then I can grade yours.</p>
    </paragraphs>

    <!-- <paragraphs>
        <title>Contribution to the Book</title>
        <p>The details of this assignment are at <xref text="title" ref="section-contributions"/>. You will write some content that could be added to our textbook. This assignment is worth <quantity><mag>6</mag><unit base="percent"/></quantity> of your final grade.</p>
    </paragraphs> -->

    <paragraphs>
        <title>Exams</title>
        <p>Please refer to the <xref ref="section-calendar" text="title"/> for exam dates, and <xref text="title" ref="section-exams"/> for details about what is covered on each exam. Exams 1, 2, and 3 are each worth <quantity><mag>25</mag><unit base="percent"/></quantity>, of your grade.</p>
    </paragraphs>

</section>
