<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<section xml:id="grades">
  <title>Grades</title>
  <p>
    General PCC Grading Guidelines are found at
    <url href="http://catalog.pcc.edu/handbook/g301-gradingguidelines/" visual="catalog.pcc.edu/handbook/g301-gradingguidelines"/>.
  </p>
  <paragraphs>
    <title>Video Lecture Notes (4%)</title>
    <p>
      Just as with in-person classes, taking notes during the lectures helps students understand and
      retain information. Each section has lecture notes that accompany YouTube videos. Print these
      lecture note outlines and fill them in as you watch the videos. (Or annotate a PDF digitally.)
      Post them to the appropriate place in D2L each week.
    </p>
  </paragraphs>
  <paragraphs>
    <title>Online Homework (24%)</title>
    <p>
      You have online homework for each section using <webwork/>. See
      <xref ref="section-webwork" text="title"/> for details. The due date for each assignment is
      posted in <webwork/>. Usually, more than one section will be due at the same time. You should
      start working on a homework assignment soon after the class that is associated with that
      section of the book.
    </p>
  </paragraphs>
  <paragraphs>
    <title>Worksheets (24%)</title>
    <p>
      Each week there is a worksheet to complete and turn in. You are encouraged to work with your
      group partners on these assignments (using Discord, Zoom, email, whatever works), and check
      each other's work before turning yours in.
    </p>
  </paragraphs>
  <paragraphs>
    <title>Exams (24% + 24%)</title>
    <p>
      There is a midterm exam and a final exam. Each exam is proctored. Most students will use
      <q>remote proctoring</q> and take the exams from home, with a video feed that shows your work
      area. See <xref ref="section-exams"/> for possible alternative arrangements.
    </p>
  </paragraphs>
  <paragraphs>
    <title>Grading Options</title>
    <p>
      Students are solely responsible for adding, dropping, or withdrawing from any class, as well
      as for selecting their desired grading option. Please review
      <url href="http://www.pcc.edu/enroll/registration/policies.html" visual="www.pcc.edu/enroll/registration/policies.html">PCC Registration Policy</url>
      for more information.
    </p>
  </paragraphs>
  <paragraphs>
    <title>Letter Grades</title>
    <p>
      Your letter grade will be assigned based on the weighted average of the items above.
    </p>
    <tabular>
      <row>
        <cell>90% and up</cell>
        <cell>A</cell>
        <cell/>
      </row>
      <row>
        <cell>80% up to 90%</cell>
        <cell>B</cell>
        <cell/>
      </row>
      <row bottom="minor">
        <cell>70% up to 80%</cell>
        <cell>C</cell>
        <cell>P</cell>
      </row>
      <row>
        <cell>60% up to 70%</cell>
        <cell>D</cell>
        <cell>N</cell>
      </row>
      <row>
        <cell>under 60%</cell>
        <cell>F</cell>
        <cell/>
      </row>
    </tabular>
  </paragraphs>
</section>
