<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<section xml:id="technology">
  <title>Technology Requirements</title>
  <p>
    This is an online class, so it is essential that you have access to a computer, laptop, tablet,
    or at the very least a smart phone. And you need internet access. You should use Firefox,
    Chrome, or Safari as your web browser.
  </p>
  <p>
    Ideally, your device and internet connection will work with Zoom in case we try to have a
    meeting. And you absolutely need a strong internet connection with Zoom for the proctored exams.
    If that is an obstacle, see <xref ref="section-exams"/> for alternatives.
  </p>
  <p>
    Also for the proctored exams, you must either use a computer with a detachable webcam, or be
    able to connect to the exam Zoom session twice, once with your computer and once with a device
    that has a camera (typically a phone or tablet).
  </p>
  <p>
    We will use free graphing calculator apps called
    <url href="https://www.geogebra.org/" visual="www.geogebra.org">GeoGebra</url> and
    <url href="https://www.desmos.com/" visual="www.desmos.com">Desmos</url>.
    (You may choose which one you prefer).
  </p>
  <p>
    You should have access to a printer to print the video lecture notes and worksheets. Or you
    should be comfortable with digitally annotating a PDF using a tablet or something similar.
  </p>
  <p>
    You should have access to a scanner or scanning app to upload completed worksheets.
    <url href="https://www.adobe.com/acrobat/mobile/scanner-app.html" visual="www.adobe.com/acrobat/mobile/scanner-app.html">Adobe Scan</url>
    (with
    <url href="https://www.adobe.com/accessibility/products/reader.html" visual="www.adobe.com/accessibility/products/reader.html">accessibility resources</url>)
    is a free smartphone app for scanning documents that you could use. There are many other similar
    apps you could explore. With a scanning app, you take multiple photos with your phone, then
    click something when you are done. And the app produces a single PDF file with each picture on
    its own page. 
  </p>
</section>
