<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<section xml:id="technology">
  <title>Technology Requirements</title>
  <p>
    This is an online class, so it is essential that you have access to a computer, laptop, tablet,
    or at least a smart phone. And you need internet access. You should use Firefox, Chrome, or
    Safari as your web browser.
  </p>
  <p>
    A computer/laptop that you use for this course <alert>must have the Zoom desktop client
    installed</alert> in order to take the remote proctored exams. A phone/tablet that you use for
    this course must have the Zoom mobile app installed for the same reason. <alert>It is not enough
    to use Zoom through a web browser.</alert> Check if you have Zoom installed on your device(s)
    and if you do not, see
    <url
      href="https://support.zoom.com/hc/en/article?id=zm_kb&amp;sysparm_article=KB0060928"
      visual="support.zoom.com/hc/en/article?id=zm_kb&amp;sysparm_article=KB0060928"
      >Zoom's website</url>
    for instructions on how to install it. If this is an obstacle, please reach out to me to get
    help overcoming it.
  </p>
  <p>
    For the remote proctored exams, you <alert>must</alert> either:
    <ul>
      <li>
        <p>
          use a computer with a detachable webcam; or
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>
          be able to connect to the exam Zoom session twice: once with your computer and once with a
          phone or tablet that has a camera.
        </p>
      </li>
    </ul>
    Please understand that with <em>one</em> screen you will be viewing the exam while connected to
    Zoom and sharing your screen. Then some sort of camera needs to <em>separately</em> be streaming
    your workspace area. It is impossible to use a camera that is embedded in that first screen for
    this purpose.
  </p>
  <p>
    We will use free graphing calculator apps called
    <url href="https://www.geogebra.org/" visual="www.geogebra.org">GeoGebra</url> and
    <url href="https://www.desmos.com/" visual="www.desmos.com">Desmos</url>.
    (You may choose which one you prefer).
  </p>
  <p>
    You should have access to a printer to print the video lecture notes and worksheets. Or if not,
    you should be comfortable with digitally annotating a PDF using a tablet or something similar.
    In the end, you have to post your written assignments in D2L: either scanned from paper or
    written digitally in the first place.
  </p>
  <p>
    You should have access to a scanner or scanning app to upload completed video lecture notes,
    weekly worksheet assignments, and your exam work. Even if you do the video lecture notes and
    weekly worksheets digitally, you will <alert>still have to scan</alert> your paper work during
    exams.
    <url
      href="https://www.adobe.com/acrobat/mobile/scanner-app.html"
      visual="www.adobe.com/acrobat/mobile/scanner-app.html"
      >Adobe Scan</url>
    (with
    <url
      href="https://www.adobe.com/accessibility/products/reader.html"
      visual="www.adobe.com/accessibility/products/reader.html"
      >accessibility resources</url>)
    is a free smartphone app for scanning documents that you could use. There are many other similar
    apps you could explore. With a scanning app, you take multiple photos with your phone, then
    click something when you are done. And the app produces a single PDF file with each picture on
    its own page.
  </p>
</section>
