<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<section xml:id="section-weekly-routine">
  <title>Weekly Routine</title>
  <p>
    This course is arranged with a weekly modular design. Each week, students should complete all
    assignments listed in the week's lesson <q>module</q>. On a week with an exam, things are
    different: there is a module for the exam, including practice material.
  </p>
  <p>
    Modules officially start and end at 10:00 <pm/> on Sundays unless otherwise stated in the course
    calendar. Often you will have early access to a weekly module. And after each week, you will
    retain access to a module until the term ends.
  </p>
  <p>
    Your week begins by:
    <ul>
      <li>
        <p>
          Reading assigned sections from the textbook and trying the embedded <q>Checkpoint</q>
          exercises.
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>
          Watching the recorded video lessons. This simulates attending an in-person lecture.
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>
          While you watch the video lessons, you will take notes using the <q>video lecture outline
          notes</q> that we provide in the module. You will scan and upload these notes for each
          module as part of your grade.
        </p>
      </li>
    </ul>
    You may read from the book and then watch the videos, or vice versa. It depends on your learning
    style. But you should do both before you proceed.
  </p>
  <p>
    Next, you have two forms of homework to practice the material:
    <ul>
      <li>
        <p>
          Online homework in <webwork/> that is automatically graded. You should try to complete
          these on your own, but you are welcome to reach out to me or a tutor for help.
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>
          Worksheets where you will write your explanations and solutions in full. You may work on
          these alone, but you will have a dedicated study group that you can work with too. In
          fact, for the first half of the term, you are required to collaborate to earn full
          credit.
        </p>
      </li>
    </ul>
    These assignments are due Sundays at 10:00 <pm/>. Please start early and work often on these
    tasks throughout the week. They take time for you to learn the content in a way that you will
    hold onto it.
  </p>
  <p>
    Throughout the week, use the General Discussions area to ask questions about any of the tasks or
    content. While you could use Discord to start a discussion, you will have less access to math
    notation there and not all students in the course will be using Discord. So the D2L General
    Discussions area is preferred. You may also email me with any questions you have.
  </p>
</section>
