<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<section xml:id="section-weekly-routine">
  <title>Weekly Routine</title>
  <p>
    This course has a weekly modular design. Each week, students should complete all assignments
    listed in the week's <q>module</q>. On a week before an exam, things are different: there is
    a preparation assignment for the exam.
  </p>
  <p>
    Modules officially start and end at 10:00 <pm/> on Sundays. Often you will have early access to
    a weekly module. And after each week, you retain access to old modules until the term ends.
  </p>
  <p>
    Your week begins by:
    <ul>
      <li>
        <p>
          Reading assigned sections from the textbook and trying the embedded <q>Checkpoint</q>
          exercises. I cannot truly verify that you do this. All I can tell you is that successful
          students complete the reading before they dive into assigned exercises.
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>
          Watching the recorded video lessons. This simulates attending an in-person lecture. While
          watching the video lessons, you'll take notes using the <q>video lecture outline notes</q>
          that are provided in the module. You will scan and upload these notes for each module.
        </p>
      </li>
    </ul>
    You may read from the book and then watch the videos, or vice versa. It depends on your learning
    style. <alert>But you should read <em>and</em> watch the videos before you proceed to homework
    assignments.</alert>
  </p>
  <p>
    You have two forms of homework:
    <ul>
      <li>
        <p>
          Online homework in <webwork/> that is automatically graded. You should try to complete
          these on your own, but you are welcome to reach out to me or a tutor for help.
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>
          Worksheets where you will write your explanations and solutions in full. You may work on
          these alone, but you will have a dedicated study group that you can work with too. In
          fact, for all worksheets before the first midterm, you are <em>required</em> to
          collaborate with your study group to earn full credit.
        </p>
      </li>
    </ul>
    These assignments are due Sundays at 10:00 <pm/>. Please start early and work often on these
    tasks throughout the week. They take time for you to learn the content in a way that you will
    hold onto it.
  </p>
  <p>
    All assignments for a weekly module are <alert>due at 10:00pm</alert> Sunday night. Assignments
    cannot be completed or turned in late. Exceptions can be made if you've had a medical or family
    emergency, but in general there won't be an exception to meeting the weekly deadline. In the
    past I accepted assignments late, and I found that this enabled students to put off work for the
    course until it snowballed into something that was impossible to complete in time. So I want you
    to understand going into the course: complete your assignments each week ahead of the due date
    so that you won't have zero scores.
  </p>
  <p>
    Throughout the week, consider reaching out for help in the following ways:
    <ul>
      <li>
        <p>the <q>Ask a Question</q> Discussion area in D2L</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>contacting people in your study group</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>free tutoring from PCC at
          <url href="https://pcc.edu/tutoring" visual="pcc.edu/tutoring"/></p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>contacting me over email</p>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </p>
</section>
