<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!-- This file is part of Alex Jordan's syllabus -->

<section xml:id="section-exams" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
    <title>Exams</title>

    <paragraphs>
        <title>Introduction</title>
        <p>
            Please see the <xref ref="section-calendar" text="title"/> for the exam dates.
        </p>
        <p><dl>
            <li xml:id="exam1">
                <title>Exam 1 (15%)</title>
                <p>
                    Covers sections 1.1<ndash/>1.9. You will have the first 80 minutes of class time.
                    The exam will have 8 or fewer exercises. Expect questions that ask the following,
                    all subject to the constraint that overall, the exam is reasonable for 80 minutes.
                    <ul>
                        <li>
                            <p>
                                Given a system of linear equations with <ellipsis/>
                                <ul>
                                    <li>
                                        <p>
                                            a unique solution, use an augmented matrix and row
                                            reduction to solve it.
                                        </p>
                                    </li>
                                    <li>
                                        <p>
                                            no solution, begin the process of using an augmented
                                            matrix and row reduction to solve it. But recognize when
                                            you can stop and conclude there is no solution.
                                        </p>
                                    </li>
                                    <li>
                                        <p>
                                            infinitely many solutions, use an augmented matrix and
                                            row reduction to solve it. Express the solution set with
                                            a vector parametrization and describe it geometrically.
                                        </p>
                                    </li>
                                </ul>
                            </p>
                        </li>
                        <li>
                            <p>
                                If you are presented with one of: a system of linear equations, an
                                augmented matrix, a vector equation, a matrix equation; be able to
                                write down something equivalent in three other forms.
                            </p>
                        </li>
                        <li>
                            <p>
                                Set up an appropriate matrix or equation to answer questions like:
                                <ul>
                                    <li>
                                        <p>Is <m>\vec{b}</m> a linear combination of <m>\vec{v}_1,\ldots,\vec{v}_p</m>? Or of the columns of matrix <m>A</m>?</p>
                                    </li>
                                    <li>
                                        <p>Is <m>\vec{b}</m> in the span of <m>\vec{v}_1,\ldots,\vec{v}_p</m>? Or in the span of the columns of matrix <m>A</m>?</p>
                                    </li>
                                    <li>
                                        Does <m>\{\vec{v}_1,\ldots,\vec{v}_p\}</m> (or the columns of a given matrix <m>A</m>) span all of <m>\mathbb{R}^n</m>?
                                    </li>
                                    <li>
                                        For a given <m>A</m> and <m>\vec{b}</m>, is <m>A\vec{x}=\vec{b}</m> guaranteed to have a solution? Must a solution to <m>A\vec{x}=\vec{b}</m> be unique?
                                    </li>
                                    <li>
                                        Is the set <m>\{\vec{v}_1,\ldots,\vec{v}_p\}</m> (or the columns of <m>A</m>) linearly independent?
                                    </li>
                                    <li>
                                        For a given linear transformation <m>T</m> does <m>T(\vec{x})=\vec{b}</m> have a solution? Must a solution to <m>T(\vec{x})=\vec{b}</m> be unique?
                                    </li>
                                    <li>
                                        Is a given linear transformation <m>T</m> one-to-one? Is it onto?
                                    </li>
                                </ul>
                            </p>
                        </li>
                        <li>
                            Demonstrate you have internalized what Theorem 4 from Section 1.4 says.
                        </li>
                        <li>
                            Demonstrate you understand the actual definition of linear independence.
                        </li>
                        <li>
                            Demonstrate you understand the two defining features of a linear transformation.
                        </li>
                        <li>
                            Evaluate a given linear transformation <m>T</m> applied to a particular vector <m>\vec{u}</m>.
                        </li>
                        <li>
                            Given a linear transformation <m>T</m>, solve the equation <m>T(\vec{x})=\vec{b}</m> for a particular <m>\vec{b}</m>.
                        </li>
                        <li>
                            Given a linear transformation <m>T</m> from <m>\mathbb{R}^n</m> to <m>\mathbb{R}^m</m>, produce its standard matrix.
                        </li>

                    </ul>
                </p>
                <p>
                    As you turn in your exam, you will be given the complete list of exercises to
                    take home with you. You may redo <em>one</em> question and turn in your response
                    the next class period to replace your original score for that question.
                </p>
            </li>
            <li xml:id="exam2">
                <title>Exam 2 (15%)</title>
                <p>
                    Covers sections 2.1<ndash/>2.3, 2.8<ndash/>2.9, 3.1<ndash/>3.2.
                </p>
                <p>
                    This exam will be given to you on Monday, to take home, complete on paper, and
                    return to me on Wednesday. You should plan to spend three hours total on the
                    exam, but that is not a time limit.
                </p>
                <p>
                    While working on this exam, you may <em>not</em> get assistance from other
                    people, AI tools, or general internet resources.
                </p>
                <p>
                    However while working on this exam, you <em>may</em> reference your notes, the
                    textbook (including through our D2L course portal to RedShelf), your <webwork/>
                    exercises, and your written homework with its feedback. You may also use a
                    linear algebra-capable calculator that can do things like row reduction. Either
                    a hand-held one, or the one in this syllabus at <xref ref="section-sage"/>.
                </p>
            </li>
            <li xml:id="exam3">
                <title>Exam 3 (15%)</title>
                <p>
                    Covers sections 4.2<ndash/>4.6, 5.1<ndash/>5.4.
                </p>
                <p>
                    This exam will be given to you on Monday, to take home, complete on paper, and
                    return to me on Wednesday. You should plan to spend three hours total on the
                    exam, but that is not a time limit.
                </p>
                <p>
                    While working on this exam, you may <em>not</em> get assistance from other
                    people, AI tools, or general internet resources.
                </p>
                <p>
                    However while working on this exam, you <em>may</em> reference your notes, the
                    textbook (including through our D2L course portal to RedShelf), your <webwork/>
                    exercises, and your written homework with its feedback. You may also use a
                    linear algebra-capable calculator that can do things like row reduction. Either
                    a hand-held one, or the one in this syllabus at <xref ref="section-sage"/>.
                </p>
            </li>
            <li xml:id="exam4">
                <title>Exam 4 (15%)</title>
                <p>
                    Covers everything, but primarily content from first three exams plus
                    sections 6.1<ndash/>6.4.
                </p>
                <p>
                    You will have the entire 120 minutes of allotted final exam time (which goes
                    from 9:00<ndash />11:00).
                </p>
                <p>
                    Unlike some previous exams, there is no opportunity to make up one question.
                </p>
            </li>
        </dl></p>
    </paragraphs>
    <paragraphs>
        <title>Missing an Exam</title>
        <p>
            If you miss an exam unexpectedly, contact me to explain why as soon as is reasonable
            given whatever the curcumstances are, or I might not be able to allow a make-up and you
            would receive a zero.
        </p>
    </paragraphs>
    <paragraphs>
        <title>Accommodated Testing</title>
        <p>
            Students who experience disability-related barriers should contact PCC's AEDR office:
            <url href="http://www.pcc.edu/disability" visual="www.pcc.edu/disability"/>.  If
            students elect to use approved academic adjustments, they must provide, in advance,
            formal notification from AEDR to the instructor. Exam accommodations may include, but
            are not limited to, extended time and a distraction-free environment.
        </p>
    </paragraphs>
</section>
