<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!-- This file is part of Alex Jordan's syllabus -->

<section xml:id="section-grades" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
    <title>Grades</title>
    <p>
        General PCC Grading Guidelines are found at
        <url href="http://catalog.pcc.edu/handbook/g301-gradingguidelines/" visual="catalog.pcc.edu/handbook/g301-gradingguidelines"/>.
    </p>

    <paragraphs>
        <title>WeBWorK</title>
        <p>
            Most of your homework for this class is submitted online through the free program
            <webwork/>. For details, see <xref ref="section-webwork" text="title"/>. Collectively,
            all web assignments are worth <quantity><mag>20</mag><unit base="percent"/></quantity>
            of your final grade.
        </p>
        <p>
            Unless a <webwork/> exercise explicitly asks you to use technology (a graphing app, or
            a CAS like SageMath) the expectation is that you do all of the exercise by hand. Don't
            deny yourself the chance to practice these exercises by hand<mdash/>on exams you will
            have to complete the exercises by hand too.
        </p>
    </paragraphs>

    <paragraphs>
        <title>Written Assignments</title>
        <p>
            Exercises from the textbook (and perhaps occasionally from somewhere else) will be
            assigned to you to write up formally. The priority with these is to practice and develop
            your writing and explanation skills. Collectively, these exercises are worth
            <quantity><mag>20</mag><unit base="percent"/></quantity>. See
            <xref text="title" ref="section-written-assignments"/> for the specifics.
        </p>
        <p>
            You may turn in written assignments in person, or upload your work to D2L.
        </p>
        <p>
            If your score on an exercise from a written assignment is less than 3/4 and you are
            unhappy with it, you may redo that exercise from scratch and turn it in again, up to two
            weeks following the original due date. (By <q>from scratch</q>, I meant that you may not
            take your graded first attempt and scratch out things, pencil in more things, etc. Make
            a clean new attempt.)
        </p>
    </paragraphs>

    <paragraphs>
        <title>Late Homework</title>
        <p>
            <webwork/> assignments are due whenever <webwork/> says they are due. If you need an
            extension, you can ask me about that and it's usually no problem.
        </p>
        <p>
            Written assignments have due dates to help you pace yourself and not become overwhelmed.
            If you need to turn in a written assignment late, that is OK as long as it is less than
            two weeks late.
        </p>
        <p>
            If you find that you are routinely late with assignments, it is a sign that you may be 
            at risk for not passing the course. And I would recommend looking into your weekly
            schedule to find a different routine.
        </p>
    </paragraphs>

    <paragraphs>
        <title>Exams</title>
        <p>
            Please refer to the <xref ref="section-calendar" text="title"/> for exam dates, and
            <xref text="title" ref="section-exams"/> for details about what is covered on each exam.
            Each of the four exams is worth <quantity><mag>15</mag><unit base="percent"/></quantity>
            of your grade.
        </p>
    </paragraphs>
</section>
