<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!-- This file is part of Alex Jordan's syllabus -->
   
<section xml:id="section-webwork" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
    <title>WeBWorK Assignments</title>

    <introduction>
        <p>I have made an account for you on a program called <webwork/> at <url href="https://webwork.pcc.edu/webwork2/mth261-jordan-201703/">webwork.pcc.edu/webwork2/mth261-jordan-201703</url>. Each week I will assign problem sets and you are required to answer them online using <webwork/>. The topics that we cover in a week have exercises that are typically due in the middle of the following week at 10:00 <init>p.m.</init> on the night in between the days we meet, but can be worked on much earlier. You may submit answers any time before the due date.  You may work from home or use PCC computer labs to turn in your answers.</p>

        <p>Here is an example of what a <webwork/> problem is like.</p>

        <exercise xml:id="webwork-demo">
            <title>Multiply Powers</title>

            <webwork>
                <pg-macros>
                    <macro-file>contextLimitedPolynomial.pl</macro-file>
                </pg-macros>

                <setup>
                    <var name="$a">
                        <static>4</static>
                    </var>
                    <var name="$b">
                        <static>3</static>
                    </var>
                    <var name="$c">
                        <static>7</static>
                    </var>
                    <var name="$expression">
                        <static>x^4\cdot x^3</static>
                    </var>
                    <var name="$answer" category="formula">
                        <static>x^7</static>
                    </var>

                    <pg-code>
                        $a = 4;
                        $b = 3;
                        $c = $a + $b;
                        $expression = Formula("x^($a)*x^($b)");

                        Context("LimitedPolynomial-Strict");
                        # custom error message
                        Context()->{error}{msg}{"A variable can appear only once in each term of a polynomial"}
                            = "Your answer must be fully simplified";

                        $answer = Formula("x^($c)");
                        $product = $a*$b;
                        $evaluator = $answer->cmp()->withPostFilter(AnswerHints(
                            [Compute("x^($product)")] =>
                            "When multiplying terms with the same base, you do not multiply the exponents."));
                    </pg-code>
                </setup>

                <statement>
                    <p>Use the properties of exponents to simplify <m><var name="$expression" /></m>.</p>
                    <p><m><var name="$expression" />=</m><var name="$answer" evaluator="$evaluator" width="8" /></p>
                </statement>

                <solution>
                    <p>We <em>add</em> the exponents as follows:</p>
                    <md>
                        <mrow><var name="$expression" />&amp;=x^{<var name="$a" />+<var name="$b" />}</mrow>
                        <mrow>&amp;=x^{<var name="$c" />}</mrow>
                    </md>
                </solution>
            </webwork>
        </exercise>
    </introduction>


    <subsection>
        <title>Why are we using <webwork/>?</title>

        <p>Traditionally, homework comes from textbook problems that students do on paper, and then turn in in to the instructor. Some bad consequences of working homework this ways are:<ul>
            <li>
                <p>It may be a week later until students get any feedback, and at that point students are no longer actively thinking about material from two weeks earlier.</p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p>It is impossible for a student to do the appropriate amount of homework <em>and</em> for the instructor to give quality feedback on every single exercise. Often an instructor is only able to give feedback for a small subset of the exercises.</p>
            </li>
        </ul></p>

        <p>Using <webwork/> brings the following advantages over traditional homework.<dl>
            <li>
                <title>Cost</title>
                <p><webwork/> is free, unlike most online homework programs.</p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <title>Timely Feedback</title>
                <p>Rather than waiting a week for written feedback from your instructor, you get instant feedback from <webwork/>.</p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <title>Quality Feedback</title>
                <p><webwork/> will do more than just tell you if you are right or wrong.  For example, it will usually tell you if you haven't completely simplified an answer or forgot to include units when they are required. Sometimes it will do even more. Try entering <c>x^12</c> as the answer to <xref text="type-global" ref="webwork-demo"/>.</p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <title>Ease of Communication</title>
                <p><webwork/> encourages you to write your instructor for help, who can provide even higher quality feedback based on your message and your previous attempts.</p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <title>Multiple or Unlimited Attempts</title>
                <p>On paper, when you submit an answer, that's the end of it. With <webwork/> you might get a problem wrong on your first attempt, but you are encouraged to figure out your mistakes and try again.</p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <title>Efficient Use of Class Time</title>
                <p>Your instructor can monitor the whole class and see in real-time which problems and concepts are causing the class difficulty.</p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <title>Extra Practice</title>
                <p>Your instructor can set things up so that you can retry each problem with new random numbers involved. If you are unsure if you have mastered a skill, this gives you a way to keep practicing.</p>
            </li>
        </dl></p>
    </subsection>

    <subsection>
        <title>Logging in to <webwork/></title>

        <p>Click any of the <webwork/> logos on this page, or go directly to <url href="https://webwork.pcc.edu/webwork2/mth261-jordan-201703">webwork.pcc.edu/webwork2/mth261-jordan-201703</url>. If you are working at your own
computer, you might want to bookmark this link. Your username is your PCC email prefix, using all lowercase letters.  For example, mine is <c>alex.jordan</c> because my email address is <email>alex.jordan@pcc.edu</email>. Your initial password is your PCC G-number, using a capital <c>G</c>.</p>
    </subsection>

    <subsection>
        <title>The First Time You Log On</title>
        <p>You should go to the <c>User Settings</c> menu in the upper left and change your password.  There is an Orientation assignment for you to take. Click on the Orientation, and begin by reading the paragraph to the right that says <q>Read This First</q>. Take the time to complete the Orientation, and you will understand a lot about how <webwork/> behaves.  The Orientation will remain available to you for the entire term, so you can always come back and look at it again.</p>
    </subsection>

    <subsection>
        <title>Homework Sets Menu</title>
        <p>This shows you the assignments that have been assigned to you and when they are due. You may:<ul>
            <li>
                <p>click on an assignment and begin working on problems online</p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p>check the box next to an assignment and click <c>Download Hardcopy</c> to get the assignment as a <c>.pdf</c> file which you may then print to work on away from a computer.</p>
            </li>
        </ul></p>
        <p>When you click on an assignment, you will see a screen with the problem numbers listed. Off to the right is a message for you that might have specific instructions or information about the assignment. You should always look for and read this message.</p>
    </subsection>

    <subsection>
        <title>Emailing for Help</title>
        <p>When you are stumped, you can click the <c>Email Instructor</c> button at the bottom of any problem. Write a message explaining what you have tried and if possible, include the work from your calculations. <webwork/> will send your instructor an email with helpful information (like all of the incorrect attempts you have tried) and they get back to you soon with a response. When they respond, it will be with an email, so <alert>you must remember to check your email</alert>.</p>
    </subsection>

    <subsection>
        <title>Math Achievements</title>
        <p>As you complete more problems through the term, you will win badges for various <q>achievements</q>. For example, the <q>On One Hand</q> badge is for completing a homework set with fewer than five incorrect submissions.  Both earning badges and just plain answering questions correctly will earn you <q>achievement points</q>. As you gain more achievement points, you will level up. Each time you level up, you earn an item that can be used to affect your grade.</p>
        <p><dl>
            <li>
                 <title>Level 1: Lesser Rod of Revelation</title>
                 <p>Give yourself 50<percent/> credit on one problem.</p>
            </li>
            <li>
                 <title>Level 2: Potion of Forgetfulness</title>
                 <p>Drop the number incorrect attempts down to <m>0</m>.</p>
            </li>
            <li>
                 <title>Level 3: Tunic of Extension</title>
                 <p>Extend the due date of a currently open homework for <m>24</m> hours.</p>
            </li>
            <li>
                 <title>Level 4: Cupcake of Enlargement</title>
                 <p>Double the weight of one problem.</p>
            </li>
            <li>
                 <title>Level 5: Box of Transmogrification</title>
                 <p>Change a single problem to be a (newly randomized) copy of a different problem on the same homework set.</p>
            </li>
            <li>
                 <title>Level 6: Greater Rod of Revelation</title>
                 <p>Give yourself 100<percent/> credit on one problem.</p>
            </li>
            <li>
                 <title>Level 7: Robe of Longevity</title>
                 <p>Extend the due date of a currently open homework for <m>48</m> hours.</p>
            </li>
            <li>
                 <title>Level 8: Scroll of Resurrection</title>
                 <p>Reopen a homework set (even a closed one) for an additional <m>24</m> hours. All problems will be re-randomized.</p>
            </li>
            <li>
                 <title>Level 9: Greater Tome of Enlightenment</title>
                 <p><q>Earn</q> 100<percent/> on every problem in a single homework set.</p>
            </li>
            <li>
                 <title>Level 10: Cake of Enlargement</title>
                 <p>Double the weight of an entire set.</p>
            </li>
        </dl></p>
    </subsection>

</section>
