<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!-- This file is part of Alex Jordan's syllabus -->

<section xml:id="section-expectations" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
    <title>Expectations</title>

    <p>
        This term we are still managing courses remotely beause of the covid-19 pandemic.
        The physical buildings at PCC are closed, and we cannot conduct in-person instruction.
    </p>

    <p>
        We all have extra responsibilities this term. As the instructor, I need to use new ways to deliver the course to you at home.
        I need to be creative and flexible with how we use technology. And you, the student, need to have self-discipline and complete
        everything that I ask of you. And also to be brave and bring all of your concerns and questions to me as soon as you can.
    </p>

    <p>
        We can boil down your responsibilities to the following list.
        <ul>
            <li>
                <p>
                    Attend the live sessions we will have in Zoom every Tuesday and Thursday at 9:00.
                    <!-- On Mondays, we will warm up with a light discussion of the
                    <url href="www.sfu.ca/~vjungic/Small-Number/">Adventures of Small Number</url>.
                    I will give a brief overview of the important points of the day, and I will take your questions,
                    including questions you have about examples and exercises.
                    Then most of the class time will be lecture/discsussion/lab.
                    The final portion of class time can be used to work collaboratively (with me or classmates)
                    on homework assignments. -->
                </p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p>
                    If you have to miss all or part of a class session, find time to watch the recording.
                </p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p>
                    For class Tuesdays, there is usually some small (and hopefully fun/interesting) thing that I ask you to do
                    before coming to class. Please do these.
                </p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p>
                    Collaborate with your classmates when it is appropriate during our live sessions.
                    When needed, continue to collaborate with your classmates outside of class.
                </p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p>
                    Complete homework (both written and <webwork/>) by its due date.
                    Work on it early so you have lead time to seek help when needed.
                </p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p>
                    Read sections of the <url href="https://spot.pcc.edu/math/ahss/ed2">textbook</url>
                    <em>ahead</em> of class.
                </p>
            </li>
            <!-- <li>
                <p>
                    Complete the weekly quiz that is assigned in <webwork/>.
                    These quizzes are supposed to let you and me know if you internalized the most important lessons from the class.
                    This will let us know if you are on track to do well with the exams.
                </p>
            </li> -->
            <li>
                <p>
                    Use all the tools available to you to communicate with me about your concerns and your questions.
                    <ul>
                        <li>Direct Email</li>
                        <li>D2L Discussion Posts (can be posted anonymously)</li>
                        <li>Raising issues during the Zoom sessions</li>
                        <li>Schedule one-on-one Zoom meeting with me</li>
                    </ul>
                </p>
            </li>
        </ul>
    </p>
</section>
