<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!-- This file is part of Alex Jordan's syllabus -->

<section xml:id="section-written-assignments" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
    <title>Written Assignments</title>
    <p>
        Please see the <xref ref="section-calendar" text="title"/> for the homework due dates.
    </p>
    <p>
        As the term progresses, more written assignments will be added to the list here. These
        should be turned in no later than their posted due dates. They can be turn in in-person, or
        uploaded in D2L.
    </p>
    <p>
        Written assignments are collectively worth 18% of your final grade. You cannot expect to do
        well in this course unless you are turning these assignments in. These are where you will
        get to develop your mathematical writing skills and work on your ability to give a
        convincing logical argument.
    </p>
    <p>
        The most important thing to understand about your written homework is that <alert>you are
        not merely finding and giving answers.</alert> You are <em>explaining to someone what the
        problem was, how you handled it, and summarizing the results.</em>  In general, your
        write-ups should respect these <q>four C's</q>:
        <dl>
            <li>
                <title>self-Containment</title>
                <p>
                    Your write-up should clearly and explicitly tell the reader what you are trying
                    to accomplish. The most straightforward way to do this is to simply copy the
                    entire exercise statement as the first thing in your write-up.
                </p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <title>Clarity</title>
                <p>
                    Am I able to read your work? Is your writing legible? Have you written
                    complete sentences that make sense, where appropriate? If you have charts,
                    graphs, and mathematical expressions, have you clearly indicated what they
                    represent? Generally, any graphs need their axes labeled with regularly spaced
                    tick marks, and they need some kind of overall title. If something about your
                    write-up causes me to pause and wonder what you mean, you will lose clarity
                    points.
                </p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <title>Convincing</title>
                <p>
                    Even if your writing is clear, it might not be logically convincing. For example,
                    <q>I rode my bike to school today, so I only had $5 in my wallet.</q> is clear in
                    the sense that the sentence structure is fine. But I don't understand why riding
                    your bike to school implies that you only have $5 in your wallet. The logical
                    progression of your write-up should convince your reader that you know what you
                    are talking about, and that each statement you write is correct based on other
                    things you have already established in your write-up.
                </p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <title>Conclusion</title>
                <p>
                    At the end of any write-up, it should be crystal clear what is your actual
                    answer to the original question. In some cases, this will mean that you should
                    write an actual conclusion sentence.
                </p>
            </li>
        </dl>
        Each exercise will be scored out of 4 points, one for each of these categories. A zero in
        some category doesn't really mean 0%, it just means I felt there was significant room for
        improvement and you coudl try again.
    </p>

    <paragraphs xml:id="written1">
        <title>Written HW 1</title>
        <p>
            This assignment has six exercises from the textbook.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 9.1 #2.</alert>
            Sketch the points <m>(0,5,2)</m>, <m>(4,0,-1)</m>, <m>(2,4,6)</m>, and <m>(1,-1,2)</m>
            on a single set of coordinate axes.
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. Look how Figure 1 in Section 9.1 is drawn. Notice how the <m>x</m>-axis and the
            <m>y</m>-axis are not symmetric (the <m>x</m>-axis is drawn in more of a downward
            direction than the <m>y</m>-axis). If you draw your axes symmetrically, it can be more
            difficult for your readers to understand that it is a three-dimensional image.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 9.2 #6.</alert>
            Copy the vectors in the figure and use them to draw the following vectors.
            <ol marker="a." cols="2">
                <li>
                    <p>
                        <m>\vec{a}+\vec{b}</m>
                    </p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>
                        <m>\vec{a}-\vec{b}</m>
                    </p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>
                        <m>\frac12\vec{a}</m>
                    </p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>
                        <m>-3\vec{b}</m>
                    </p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>
                        <m>\vec{a}+2\vec{b}</m>
                    </p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>
                        <m>2\vec{b}-\vec{a}</m>
                    </p>
                </li>
            </ol>
            [You will have to find the figure in the textbook.]
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. When drawing vectors as arrows it is not relevant where the starting position is.
            You do not need to draw all of the vectors with the same starting position (but you can
            if you want to). What matters is the direction and the length of the arrow that you
            draw.)
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 9.2 #43.</alert>
            Use vectors to prove that the line joining the midpoints of two sides of a triangle is
            parallel to the third side and half its length.
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. Sketch a triangle, preferable one that is not a right triangle and all three
            sides have different lengths. Make two of the edges into arrows that emanate from one of
            the corners. You can label these as vectors however you like. Now pick a direction to
            make the third side an arrow as well. What is this vector in terms of the labels you
            gave to the first two vectors? Continue answering the exercise now that you have this
            diagram to help you think it through.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 9.3 #14.</alert>
            A street vendor sells <m>a</m> hamburgers, <m>b</m> hot dogs, and <m>c</m> soft drinks
            on a given day. They charge $2 for a hamburger, $1.50 for a hot dog, and $1 for a soft
            drink. If <m>\vec{A}=\langle a,b,c\rangle</m> and <m>\vec{P}=\langle 2,1.5,1\rangle</m>,
            what is the meaning of the dot product <m>\vec{A}\cdot\vec{P}</m>?
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. As always, make sure you are following the <q>four C's</q> that I use to assess
            written work. Your write-up to this exercise should be more than a one-line sentence or
            phrase.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 9.3 #33.</alert>
            Show that the vector
            <m>\mathrm{orth}_{\vec{a}}\,\vec{b}=\vec{b}-\mathrm{proj}_{\vec{a}}\,\vec{b}</m> is
            orthogonal to <m>\vec{a}</m>. (It is called an <term>orthogonal projection</term> of
            <m>\vec{b}</m>.
        </p>
        <p>
            This exercise is defining what <m>\mathrm{orth}_{\vec{a}}\,\vec{b}</m> means in terms of
            <m>\mathrm{proj}_{\vec{a}}\,\vec{b}</m> which is defined in the section. Your job is to
            convince the reader that <m>\mathrm{orth}_{\vec{a}}\,\vec{b}</m> and <m>\vec{a}</m> are
            orthogonal.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 9.4 #18.</alert>
            Find the vector, not with determinants, but by using properties of cross products.
            <me>(\hat{\imath}+\hat{\jmath})\times(\hat{\imath}-\hat{\jmath})</me>
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. Do not answer this by writing <m>\hat{\imath}</m> as <m>\langle1,0,0\rangle</m>,
            etc. Instead, use the algebraic properties of the cross product (these are listed in a
            box in the section, following Example 2). At some point, you will have to think about
            the vectors <m>\hat{\imath}</m>, <m>\hat{\jmath}</m>, and <m>\hat{k}</m>; and the
            right-hand rule and how they interact with eachother via the cross product. How you find
            the final answer should be explained to your reader.
        </p>
    </paragraphs>
    <paragraphs xml:id="written2">
        <title>Written HW 2</title>
        <p>
            This assignment has four exercises from the textbook.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 9.5 #34.</alert>
            Use intercepts to help sketch the plane. <m>3x+y+2z=6</m>
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. This should be done by hand, not with a computer plotting it for you. Figure
            7 might be a model for you to follow. However you should make it clear that you are
            plotting an entire plane, not just a triangle.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 9.5 #61.</alert>
            Show that the lines with symmetric equations <m>x=y=z</m> and <m>x+1=y/2=z/3</m> are
            skew, and find the distance between these lines.
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. To show that the two lines are skew, first you could assume that they are
            <em>not</em> skew. So you could assume there are some specific numbers <m>x_0</m>,
            <m>y_0</m>, and <m>z_0</m> that are on both of the two lines. What does the first line's
            symmetric equtaions tell you about <m>x_0</m>, <m>y_0</m>, and <m>z_0</m>? And then
            what does the second line's symmetric equtaions tell you about <m>x_0</m>, <m>y_0</m>,
            and <m>z_0</m>?
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 9.6 #7.</alert>
            Find and sketch the domain of the function <m>f(x,y)=\sqrt{1-x^2}-\sqrt{1-y^2}</m>.
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. This should be done by hand, not with a computer plotting it for you. You are
            plotting a 2D image because you are plotting the domain of this function of two
            variables. You should explain to your reader with some words (and possibly math
            expressions) how you know that the domain you sketch is
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 9.6 #12.</alert>
            Sketch a graph of the function <m>f(x,y)=\cos(x)</m>.
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. This should be done by hand, not with a computer plotting it for you. Notice how
            <m>y</m> is not present in the function's formula. So you could plot one <q>rib</q> of
            the graph for <m>y=0</m> and then know that more <q>ribs</q> are just translations of
            that first rib in the <m>y</m>-direction.
        </p>
    </paragraphs>
    <paragraphs xml:id="written3">
        <title>Written HW 3</title>
        <p>
            This assignment has seven exercises from the textbook.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 9.7 #4.</alert>
            Plot the point whose cylindrical coordinates are given. Then find the rectangular
            coordinates of the point.
            <ol marker="a.">
                <li>
                    <p>
                        <m>(1,\pi,e)</m>
                    </p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>
                        <m>(1,3\pi/2,2)</m>
                    </p>
                </li>
            </ol>
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. This should be done by hand, not with a computer plotting it for you. Your image
            should make it clear to a reader how each of the three cylindrical coordinate values
            are present in your picture.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 9.7 #26.</alert>
            Sketch the solid described by the given inequalities. <m>0\leq\theta\leq\pi/2</m>,
            <m>r\leq z\leq2</m>.
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. This should be done by hand, not with a computer plotting it for you. You might
            want to sketch the solid from more than one angle, unless you feel that your first
            sketch does a good job of fully communicating the shape. The first inequality here tells
            you something about which octants this shape can be in. With the second inequality, I
            suggest imagining a few fixed values for <m>z</m>, like <m>z=0</m>, <m>z=1</m>, and
            <m>z=2</m>. Each of these is a plane, and then you get to understand what a certain
            cross-section of the sold looks like.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 10.1 #6.</alert>
            Sketch the curve with the given vector equation. Indicate with an arrow the direction in
            which <m>t</m> increases. <m>\vec{r}(t)=\langle t^2, t^3\rangle</m>.
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. This should be done by hand, not with a computer plotting it for you.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 10.1 #8.</alert>
            Sketch the curve with the given vector equation. Indicate with an arrow the direction in
            which <m>t</m> increases. <m>\vec{r}(t)=\langle \sin\pi t, t, \cos \pi t\rangle</m>.
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. This should be done by hand, not with a computer plotting it for you.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 10.1 #25.</alert>
            Show that the curve with parameteric equations <m>x=t\cos t</m>, <m>y=t\sin t</m>,
            <m>z=t</m> lies on eth cone <m>z^2=x^2+y^2</m>, and use this fact to help sketch the
            curve.
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. This should be done by hand, not with a computer plotting it for you.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 10.2 #1.</alert>
            The figure shows a curve <m>C</m> given by a vector function <m>\vec{r}(t)</m>.
            <ol marker="a.">
                <li>
                    <p>
                        Draw the vectors <m>\vec{r}(4.5)-\vec{r}(4)</m> and
                        <m>\vec{r}(4.2)-\vec{r}(4)</m>.
                    </p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>
                        Draw the vectors <m>\frac{\vec{r}(4.5)-\vec{r}(4)}{0.5}</m> and
                        <m>\frac{\vec{r}(4.2)-\vec{r}(4)}{0.2}</m>.
                    </p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>
                        Write expressions for <m>\vec{r}'(4)</m> and the unit tangent vector
                        <m>\vec{T}(4)</m>.
                    </p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>
                        Draw the vector <m>\vec{T}(4)</m>.
                    </p>
                </li>
            </ol>
            [You will have to find the figure in the textbook.]
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. Copy the figure from the textbook exactly. If you prefer, you can print a
            picture of that figure. But then you must hand draw what is asked of you. The image
            might become cluttered, and it might help with your clarity if you make separate
            pictures for parts (a), (b), and (d). In part (c), one of the two expressions involves
            the limit operator, and the other can just reference the first. 
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 10.2 #4.</alert>
            <ol marker="a.">
                <li>
                    <p>
                        Sketch the plane curve <m>\vec{r}(t)=\langle 1+t, \sqrt{t}\rangle</m>.
                    </p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>
                        Find <m>\vec{r}'(t)</m>.
                    </p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>
                        Sketch the position vector <m>\vec{r}(t)</m> and the tangent vector
                        <m>\vec{r}'(t)</m> for <m>t=1</m>.
                    </p>
                </li>
            </ol>
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. This should be done by hand. In part (c), recall that you can sketch the same
            vector in multiple places if you like.
        </p>
    </paragraphs>
    <paragraphs xml:id="written4">
        <title>Written HW 4</title>
        <p>
            This assignment has four exercises from the textbook.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 10.3 #16.</alert>
            Reparametrize the curve
            <me>\vec{r}(t)=\left(\frac{2}{t^2+1}-1\right)\hat{\imath}+\frac{2t}{t^2+1}\hat{\jmath}</me>
            with respect to arc length measured from the point <m>(1,0)</m> in the direction of
            increasing <m>t</m>. Express the reparametrization in the simplest form. What can you
            conclude about the curve?
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. First you will apply the procedure for parametrizing by arc length. You will need
            several trig identitites to simplify the reparametrized expression, and here are some
            that may help: <m>\tan^2(x)+1=\sec^2(x)</m>, <m>\frac{1}{\sec(x)}=\cos(x)</m>,
            <m>\tan(x)\cos(x)=\sin(x)</m>, <m>2\cos^2(x/2)-1=\cos(x)</m>,
            <m>2\sin(x/2)\cos(x/2)=\sin(x)</m>.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 10.3 #30.</alert>
            At what point does the curve <m>y=\ln x</m> have the maximum curvature? What happens to
            the curvature as <m>x\to\infty</m>?
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. This curve is expressed as <m>y=f(x)</m>, so it is convenient to find its
            curvature at <m>x</m> using Formula 11 form the section. Once you locate where the
            curvature is maximal, you should inlcude a plot of this function and mark where that
            maximal curvature happens. Visually, it should seem reasonable that the curvature is
            maximal there. Don't miss the last part of this exercise about <m>x\to\infty</m>. Your
            answer to that part should come from your curvature formula, but also the graph should
            visually validate your answer.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 10.3 #33.</alert>
            <ol marker="a.">
                <li>
                    <p>
                        Is the curvature of the curve <m>C</m> shown in the figure greater at
                        <m>P</m> or at <m>Q</m>? Explain.
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        [You will have to find the figure in the textbook.]
                    </p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    Estimate the curvature at <m>P</m> and at <m>Q</m> by sketching the osculating
                    circles at those points.
                </li>
            </ol>
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. For part (b), recall that the radius of the osculating circle at a point is the
            reciprocal of the curvature at that point.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 10.3 #49.</alert>
            Find the equations of the osculating circles of the ellipse <m>9x^2+4y^2=36</m> at the
            points <m>(2,0)</m> and <m>(0,3)</m>. Use a graphing calculator or computer to graph
            the ellipse and both osculating circles on the same screen.
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. If you divide each side of the ellipse equation by <m>36</m>, it will be in
            standard form where you can identify the two radii of the ellipse. Use what you know
            about circular motion to parametrize the curve with a parameter <m>t</m>. (I do not
            recommend solving the ellipse equaiton for <m>y</m> and using Formula 11 to find
            curvature. In theory that would work but the formulas will be messy and you would have
            to take a limit as <m>x</m> approaches <m>2</m> from below.)
        </p>
        <p>
            In your graph, the circles ought to look like they fit well with the ellipse. If not, it
            is a sign that you made an error.
        </p>
    </paragraphs>
    <paragraphs xml:id="written5">
        <title>Written HW 5</title>
        <p>
            This assignment has six exercises from the textbook.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 10.4 #2.</alert>
            The figure shows the path of a particle that moves with position vector
            <m>\vec{r}(t)</m> at time <m>t</m>.
        </p>
        <p>
            [You will have to find the figure in the textbook.]
        </p>
        <p>
            <ol marker="a.">
                <li>
                    <p>
                        Draw a vector that represents the average velocity of the particle over the
                        time interval <m>2\leq t\leq2.4</m>.
                    </p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>
                        Draw a vector that represents the average velocity of the particle over the
                        time interval <m>1.5\leq t\leq2</m>.
                    </p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>
                        Write an expression for the velocity vector <m>\vec{v}(2)</m>.
                    </p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>
                        Draw an approxiamtion to the vector <m>\vec{v}(2)</m> and estimate the speed
                        of the particle at <m>t=2</m>.
                    </p>
                </li>
            </ol>
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. When you draw the vectors that are asked for in (a) and (b), draw them with their
            tails at the appropriate place: <m>\vec{r}(2)</m>. Remember that when <m>0.4</m> units
            of time pass, and you divide by <m>0.4</m>, that is the same as multiplying by
            <m>2.5</m>. Take note that the two axes have a scale, so it is possible for you to
            estimate how long things are that you draw.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 10.4 #26.</alert>
            A batter hits a baseball <m>3</m> ft above the ground toward the center field fence,
            which is <m>10</m> ft high and <m>400</m> ft from home plate. The ball leaves the bat
            with speed <m>115</m> ft/s at an angle of <m>50^{\circ}</m> above the horizontal. Is it
            a home run? (In other words, does the ball clear the fence?)
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. You will need to know the acceleration due to gravity on Earth in feet per second.
            You can treat this as a 2D vector problem. I recommend drawing some pictures.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 11.1 #5.</alert>
            Find and sketch the domain of the function <m>f(x,y)=\ln(9-x^2-9y^2)</m>. What is the
            range of <m>f</m>?
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 11.1 #10.</alert>
            Shown is a contour map of atmospheric pressure in North America on August 12, 2008. On
            the level curves (called isobars) the pressure is indicated in millibars (mb).
        </p>
        <p>
            [You will have to find the figure in the textbook.]
        </p>
        <p>
            <ol marker="a.">
                <li>
                    <p>
                        Estimate the pressure at <m>C</m> (Chicago), <m>N</m> (Nashville), <m>S</m>
                        (San Francisco), and <m>V</m> (Vancouver).
                    </p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>
                        At which of these locations were the winds strongest?
                    </p>
                </li>
            </ol>
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. Remember that a good introduction (which is one point for the exercise) includes
            any graphs or images that help the reader understand what your task is. For part (b),
            make sure that you explain why you have chosen a particular city.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 11.1 #27.</alert>
            Sketch both a contour map and a graph (3D) of the function and compare them.
            <me>f(x,y)=x^2+9y^2</me>
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. It may help to recall that if you have an equation of the form
            <m>\frac{x^2}{a^2}+\frac{y^2}{b^2}=1</m>, it makes an ellipse centered at the origin,
            with <m>x</m>-radius <m>a</m> and <m>y</m>-radius <m>b</m>. If you set <m>x^2+9y^2</m>
            equal to some number, you can divide by that number and then also use a little algebra
            rearrangement to get that form of an ellipse equation.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 11.2 #14.</alert>
            Find the limit, if it exists, or show that the limit does not exist.
            <me>\lim_{(x,y)\to(0,0)}\frac{xy^4}{x^2+y^8}</me>
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. Try approaching <m>(0,0)</m> using curves of the form <m>y=p(x)</m> or
            <m>y=q(x)</m>. You are trying to find two paths that reveal different limit behavior, so
            you can conclude that this limit overall does not exist.
        </p>
    </paragraphs>
    <paragraphs xml:id="written6">
        <title>Written HW 6</title>
        <p>
            This assignment has five exercises from the textbook.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 11.3 #4.</alert>
            The wave heights <m>h</m> in the open sea depend on the speed <m>v</m> of the wind and
            the length of time <m>t</m> that the wind has been blowing at that speed. Values of the
            function <m>h=f(v,t)</m> are recorded in feet in the following table.
        </p>
        <p>
            [You will have to find the table in the textbook.]
        </p>
        <p>
            <ol marker="a.">
                <li>
                    <p>
                        What are the meanings of the partial derivatives
                        <m>\frac{\partial h}{\partial v}</m> and
                        <m>\frac{\partial h}{\partial t}</m>?
                    </p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>
                        Estimate the values of <m>f_v(40,15)</m> and <m>f_t(40,15)</m>. What are the
                        practical interpretations of these values?
                    </p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>
                        What appears to be the value of the following limit?
                        <me>\lim_{t\to\infty}\frac{\partial h}{\partial t}</me>
                    </p>
                </li>
            </ol>
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. For part (a), think about the units that would be attached to each partial
            derivative.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 11.3 #5<ndash/>8.</alert>
            Determine the signs of the partial derivatives for the function <m>f</m> whose graph is
            shown.
            <ul>
                <li>
                    <p>
                        <m>f_x(1,2)</m>
                    </p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>
                        <m>f_y(1,2)</m>
                    </p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>
                        <m>f_x(-1,2)</m>
                    </p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>
                        <m>f_y(-1,2)</m>
                    </p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>
                        <m>f_{xx}(-1,2)</m>
                    </p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>
                        <m>f_{yy}(-1,2)</m>
                    </p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>
                        <m>f_{xy}(1,2)</m>
                    </p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>
                        <m>f_{xy}(-1,2)</m>
                    </p>
                </li>
            </ul>
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. For each part, you should write roughly one sentence that explains why you are
            deciding the way you are deciding. A complete introduction would include a copy of the
            given graph.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 11.3 #9.</alert>
            The following surfaces, labeled <m>a</m>, <m>b</m>, and <m>c</m>, are graphs of a
            function <m>f</m> and its partial derivatives <m>f_x</m> and <m>f_y</m>. Identify each
            surface and give reasons for your choices.
        </p>
        <p>
            [You will have to find the graphs in the textbook.]
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. A complete introduction would include copies of the given graphs. Make sure that
            you try to explain to your reader why you are making the choices you are making.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 11.3 #82.</alert>
            The wind-chill index is modeled by the function
            <me>
                W=13.12+0.6215T-11.37v^{0.16}+0.3965Tv^{0.16}
            </me>
            where <m>T</m> is the temperature (in Celsius) and <m>v</m> is the wind speed (in km/h).
            When <m>T=-15</m> and <m>v=30</m>, by how much would you expect the apparent temperature
            <m>W</m> to drop if the actual temperature decreases by <m>1^{\circ}\mathrm{C}</m>?
            What if the wind speed increases by <m>1</m> km/h?
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. This problem is all about finding partial derivatives in a real context, and
            interpreting them.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 11.4 #8.</alert>
            Graph the surface and the tangent plane at the given point. (Choose the domain and
            viewpoint so that you get a good view of both the surface and the tangent plane.) Then
            zoom in until the surface and the tangent plane become indistinguishable.
            <me>
                z=\arctan(xy^2), \qquad (1,1,\pi/4)
            </me>
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. I am expecting you to show the steps/work for finding the tangent plane's
            equation. Then use a 3D graphing app (such as GeoGebra's 3D calculator) to make two
            images. One should be from a distance, the other zoomed in as requested. Include the
            computer-generated images in your write-up.
        </p>
    </paragraphs>
    <paragraphs xml:id="written7">
        <title>Written HW 7</title>
        <p>
            This assignment has six exercises from the textbook.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 11.5 #34.</alert>
            Wheat production <m>W</m> in a given year depends on the average temperature <m>T</m>
            and the annual rainfall <m>R</m>. Scientists estimate that the average temperature is
            rising at a rate of <m>0.15^{\circ}\mathrm{C}/\mathrm{year}</m> and rainfall is
            decreasing at a rate of <m>0.1\,\mathrm{cm}/\mathrm{year}</m>. They also estimate that,
            at current prduction levels, <m>\partial W/\partial T=-2</m> and
            <m>\partial W/\partial R=8</m>.
            <ol marker="a.">
                <li>
                    <p>
                        What is the significance of the signs of these partial derivatives?
                    </p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>
                        Estimate the current rate of change of wheat production, <m>dW/dt</m>.
                    </p>
                </li>
            </ol>
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. For part (a), you are trying to say that as something increases, something else
            increases/decreases. Just be specific about what is increasing, etc.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 11.5 #42.</alert>
            If a sound with frequency <m>f_s</m> is produced by a source traveling along a line with
            speed <m>v_s</m> and an observer is traveling with speed <m>v_o</m> along the same line
            from the opposite direction toward the source, then the frequency of the sound heard by
            the observer is <me>f_o=\left(\frac{c+v_o}{c-v_s}\right)f_s</me> where <m>c</m> is the
            speed of sound, about 332 m/s. (This is the <term>Doppler effect</term>.) Suppose that,
            at a particular moment, you are in a train traveling at <m>34\,\mathrm{m}/\mathrm{s}</m>
            and accelerating at <m>1.2\,\mathrm{m}/\mathrm{s}^2</m>. A train is approaching you from
            the opposite direction on the other track at <m>40\,\mathrm{m}/\mathrm{s}</m>,
            accelerating at <m>1.4\,\mathrm{m}/\mathrm{s}^2</m>, and sounds its whistle, which has
            a frequency of <m>460\,\mathrm{Hz}</m>. At that instant, what is the perceived
            frequency that you hear and how fast is it changing?
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. You are the observer. This question asks you to find two things. One is just
            <m>f_o</m> at that moment, and you simply use the Doppler effect equatin to get that.
            But this also asks for <m>\frac{df_o}{dt}</m> at that moment, and you will use the Chain
            Rule to find it. Note that <m>c</m> and <m>f_s</m> are constants. But <m>v_o</m> and
            <m>v_s</m> are not constant.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 11.6 #32.</alert>
            Suppose you are climbing a hill whose shape is given by the equation
            <m>z=1000-0.005x^2-0.01y^2</m>, where <m>x</m>, <m>y</m>, and <m>z</m> are measured in
            meters, and you are standing on a point with coordinates <m>(60,40,966)</m>. The
            positive <m>x</m>-axis points east, and the positive <m>y</m>-axis points north.
            <ol marker="a.">
                <li>
                    <p>
                        If you walk due south, will you start to ascend or descend? At what rate?
                    </p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>
                        If you walk northwest, will you start to ascend or descend? At what rate?
                    </p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>
                        In which direction is the slope largest? What is the rate of ascent in that
                        direction? At what angle above the horizontal does the path in that
                        direction begin?
                    </p>
                </li>
            </ol>
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. Parts (a) and (b) are only asking for a certin directional derivative. Part (c)
            is asking for serveral things. You will need to understand several things about the
            gradient vector at that location to answer all of the questions in part (c).
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 11.7 #33.</alert>
            For functions of one variable it is impossible for a continuous function to have two
            local maxima and no local minimum. But for functions of two variables such functions
            exist. Show that the function <me>f(x,y)=-(x^2-1)^2-(x^2y-x-1)^2</me> has only two
            critical points, but has local maxima at both of them. Then use a computer to produce a
            graph with carefully chose domain and viewpoint to see how this is possible.
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. Is it clear why this is impossible for a continuous function of one variable?
            In between the two maxima, you would have to have a minimum. Anyway, show what is asked
            for about a two-variable function. Also, be sure to include a copy of the graph that
            you make using GeoGebra, Desmos, etc.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 11.7 #46.</alert>
            The base of an aquarium with given volume <m>V</m> is made of slate and the sides are
            made of glass. If slate costs five times as much (per unit area) as glass, find the
            dimensions of the aquarium that minimize the cost of materials.
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. At first you have three variables: <m>x, y, z</m>. But since the volume is fixed
            at <m>V</m>, you can replace <m>z</m> with <m>\frac{V}{xy}</m> and only have two
            variables. Now do something simple like assume the glass costs one dollar per unit of
            area, and calclulate the total glass cost in terms of <m>x</m> and <m>y</m>. Then do
            the same for the slate, but assuming it costs five dollars per unit area. (If the costs
            are different, it won't matter as long as the ratio of the per-unit-area costs is still
            five.) Add it all up to get the total cost, and this is the function to optimize. In
            the end, report the three dimensions of the aquarium.
        </p>
        <p>
            You <em>could</em> tackle this exercise using Lagrange multipliers from section 11.8.
            But don't do that. The purpose here is to demonstrate the approach outlined above.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 11.8 #38.</alert>
            Use Lagrange multipliers to give an alternate solution to Exercise #46 from Section 11.7.
        </p>
        <p>
            OK, now you have a function of <em>three</em> variables <m>x, y, z</m>. Rather than
            eliminate <m>z</m>, use the constraint <m>V=xyz</m>, and work with a simpler looking
            cost function that is in terms of <m>x</m>, <m>y</m>, and <m>z</m>. Make sure you get the
            same result as with the previous exercise.
        </p>
    </paragraphs>
    <paragraphs xml:id="written8">
        <title>Written HW 8</title>
        <p>
            This assignment has five exercises from the textbook.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 12.2 #32.</alert>
            Graph the solid that lies between the surface <m>z=2xy/\left(x^2+1\right)</m> and the
            plane <m>z=x+2y</m> and is bounded by the planes <m>x=0</m>, <m>x=2</m>, <m>y=0</m>, and
            <m>y=4</m>. Then find its volume.
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. You should use a 3D graphing app to plot the six surfaces that are described
            here. Typically, 3D graphing apps will use trasparency to allow you to see surfaces
            through the other side of surfaces, and you will want that to make this solid visible.
            Capture at least two images from different viewpoints so your reader can really see what
            this looks like. Then to find the volume, set up the appropriate integral and find it by
            hand.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 12.3 #38.</alert>
            Sketch the solid whose volume is given by the iterated integral
            <me>\int_0^1\int_0^{1-x^2}(1-x)\,dy\,dx</me>
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. This is <em>only</em> asking you to amke the sketch, not also find the volume
            (although that would be easy to do). You should attempt to sketch the solid by hand.
            First make your axis system in the <q>usual</q> way with the <m>x</m>-axis pointing a
            bit down and to the left, the <m>y</m>-axis pointing mostly to the right, and the 
            <m>z</m>-axis pointing up. The bounds on the iterated integral define curves/lines you
            should attempt to sketch in the <m>xy</m>-plane. The function being integrated is a
            <m>z</m>-value, and that defines for you a <q>top</q> to this object.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 12.3 #60.</alert>
            In evaluating a double integral over a region <m>D</m>, a sum of iterated integral was
            obtained as follows:
            <me>\iint_D f(x,y)\,dA=\int_0^1\int_0^{2y}f(x,y)\,dx\,dy+\int_1^3\int_0^{3-y}f(x,y)\,dx\,dy</me>
            Sketch the region <m>D</m> and express the double integral as an iterated integral with
            reversed order of integration.
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. The sketch you make for this exercise is a 2D sketch of <m>D</m>, not a 3D sketch.
            The poit of the exercise is that if you can use the sum of two iterated integrals to
            understand what the region <m>D</m> actually looks like, then if you change the order
            of integration, it is actually just a single iterated integral (not a sum of two
            iterated integrals).
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 12.4 #5.</alert>
            Sketch the region whose area is given by the integral and evaluate the integral:
            <me>\int_{\pi}^{2\pi}\int_4^7r\,dr\,d\theta</me>
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. The first step is to sketch the shape. Since the integrand is
            <m>r\,dr\,d\theta</m>, which is polar coordinates is <m>dA</m>, the limits on the two
            integrals define for you the shape. After you understand the shape, you are welcome to
            either actually do the integral using antiderivatives, or use basic geometry area
            formulas.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 12.4 #31.</alert>
            A swimming pool is circular with a <m>40</m>-ft diameter. The depth is constant along
            east-west lines and increases linearly from <m>2</m> ft at the south end to <m>7</m> ft
            at the north end. Find the volume of water in the pool.
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. You might benefit from sketching this 3D object, as well as sketching the 2D
            region over which you will integrate. You need to integrate the depth (in feet) times
            <m>dA</m>, which is in square feet. Remember to use the polar coordinates expression for
            <m>dA</m>. The depth of the pool is easiest to express as a function of <m>y</m> (given
            the orientation with the shallow end at the southern point and deep end at the northern
            point) but you will want to convert that into polar coordinates.
        </p>
    </paragraphs>
</section>
