<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!-- This file is part of Alex Jordan's syllabus -->

<section xml:id="section-exams" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
    <title>Exams</title>

    <paragraphs>
        <title>Introduction</title>
        <p>
            Please see the <xref ref="section-calendar" text="title"/> for the exam dates.
        </p>
        <p><dl>
            <li xml:id="exam1">
                <title>Exam 1 (13%)</title>
                <p>
                    Covers sections 3.9, 4.7, and 7.1<ndash/>7.5. You will have the entire class
                    period for this exam, but it will be written with the expecation that a few
                    students will need less than one hour.
                </p>
                <p>
                    As you turn in your exam, you will be given the complete list of exercises to
                    take home with you. You may redo <em>one</em> question and turn in your response
                    the next class period to replace your original score for that question.
                </p>
            </li>
            <li xml:id="exam2">
                <title>Exam 2 (13%)</title>
                <p>
                    Covers sections 8.1<ndash/>8.4. You will have the entire class
                    period for this exam, but it will be written with the expecation that a few
                    students will need less than one hour.
                </p>
                <p>
                    As you turn in your exam, you will be given the complete list of exercises to
                    take home with you. You may redo <em>one</em> question and turn in your response
                    the next class period to replace your original score for that question.
                </p>
            </li>
            <li xml:id="exam3">
                <title>Exam 3 (13%)</title>
                <p>
                    Covers sections 8.5<ndash/>8.8. You will have the entire class
                    period for this exam, but it will be written with the expecation that a few
                    students will need less than one hour.
                </p>
                <p>
                    Unlike previous exams, there is no opportunity to make up one question. I will
                    provide you with complete solutions to help you study for the final exam the
                    following week.
                </p>
            </li>
            <li xml:id="exam4">
                <title>Exam 4 (25%)</title>
                <p>
                    Covers everything from the course. The PCC math department requires a
                    comprehensive final exam worth at least 25% of your final grade. It will be
                    sufficient to be comfortable with the exercises from exams 1, 2, and 3.
                </p>
                <p>
                    You will have the entire 120 minutes of allotted final exam time (which goes
                    from 9:00<ndash />11:00).
                </p>
                <p>
                    Unlike previous exams, there is no opportunity to make up one question.
                </p>
            </li>
        </dl></p>
    </paragraphs>
    <paragraphs>
        <title>Missing an Exam</title>
        <p>
            If you miss an exam unexpectedly, contact me to explain why as soon as is reasonable
            given whatever the curcumstances are, or I might not be able to allow a make-up and you
            would receive a zero.
        </p>
    </paragraphs>
    <paragraphs>
        <title>Accommodated Testing</title>
        <p>
            Students who experience disability-related barriers should contact PCC's AEDR office:
            <url href="http://www.pcc.edu/disability" visual="www.pcc.edu/disability"/>.  If
            students elect to use approved academic adjustments, they must provide, in advance,
            formal notification from AEDR to the instructor. Exam accommodations may include, but
            are not limited to, extended time and a distraction-free environment.
        </p>
    </paragraphs>
</section>
