<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!-- This file is part of Alex Jordan's syllabus -->

<section xml:id="section-expectations" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
    <title>Expectations</title>

    <p>
        This term we are still managing many courses remotely beause of the covid-19 pandemic.
        This section is being administered remotely.
    </p>

    <p>
        We all have extra responsibilities this term.
        As the instructor, I need to use new ways to deliver the course to you at home.
        I need to be creative and flexible with how we use technology.
        And you, the student, need to have self-discipline and complete the assignments that I ask of you.
        And also to be brave and bring your concerns and questions to me as soon as you can.
    </p>

    <p>
        We can boil down your responsibilities to the following list.
        <ul>
            <li>
                <p>
                    Attend the live sessions we will have in Zoom.
                </p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p>
                    If you have to miss all or part of a class session, find time to watch the recording.
                </p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p>
                    Collaborate with your classmates when it is appropriate during our live sessions.
                    When needed, continue to collaborate with your classmates outside of class.
                </p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p>
                    Complete assignments by their due dates.
                    Work on assignments early so you have time to seek help whenever that is needed.
                </p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p>
                    Read sections of the <url href="https://opentext.uleth.ca/apex-video/apex-calculus.html" visual="opentext.uleth.ca/apex-video/apex-calculus.html">textbook</url>
                    <em>ahead</em> of class. If it suits your learning style, watch the videos there as well.
                </p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p>
                    Use all the tools available to you to communicate with me about your concerns and your questions.
                    <ul>
                        <li>Direct Email</li>
                        <li>D2L Discussion Posts (can be posted anonymously)</li>
                        <li>Raising issues during the Zoom sessions</li>
                        <li>Schedule one-on-one Zoom meeting with me</li>
                    </ul>
                </p>
            </li>
        </ul>
    </p>
</section>

