<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!-- This file is part of Alex Jordan's syllabus -->

<section xml:id="section-written-assignments" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
    <title>Written Assignments</title>
    <p>
        Please see the <xref ref="section-calendar" text="title"/> for the homework due dates.
    </p>
    <p>
        As the term progresses, more written assignments will be added to the list here. These
        should be turned in no later than their posted due dates. They can be turn in in-person, or
        uploaded in D2L.
    </p>
    <p>
        Written assignments are collectively worth 18% of your final grade. You cannot expect to do
        well in this course unless you are turning these assignments in. These are where you will
        get to develop your mathematical writing skills and work on your ability to give a
        convincing logical argument.
    </p>
    <p>
        The most important thing to understand about your written homework is that <alert>you are
        not merely finding and giving answers.</alert> You are <em>explaining to someone what the
        problem was, how you handled it, and summarizing the results.</em>  In general, your
        write-ups should respect these <q>four C's</q>:
        <dl>
            <li>
                <title>self-Containment</title>
                <p>
                    Your write-up should clearly and explicitly tell the reader what you are trying
                    to accomplish. The most straightforward way to do this is to simply copy the
                    entire exercise statement as the first thing in your write-up.
                </p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <title>Clarity</title>
                <p>
                    Am I able to read your work? Is your writing legible? Have you written
                    complete sentences that make sense, where appropriate? If you have charts,
                    graphs, and mathematical expressions, have you clearly indicated what they
                    represent? Generally, any graphs need their axes labeled with regularly spaced
                    tick marks, and they need some kind of overall title. If something about your
                    write-up causes me to pause and wonder what you mean, you will lose clarity
                    points.
                </p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <title>Convincing</title>
                <p>
                    Even if your writing is clear, it might not be logically convincing. For example,
                    <q>I rode my bike to school today, so I only had $5 in my wallet.</q> is clear in
                    the sense that the sentence structure is fine. But I don't understand why riding
                    your bike to school implies that you only have $5 in your wallet. The logical
                    progression of your write-up should convince your reader that you know what you
                    are talking about, and that each statement you write is correct based on other
                    things you have already established in your write-up.
                </p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <title>Conclusion</title>
                <p>
                    At the end of any write-up, it should be crystal clear what is your actual
                    answer to the original question. In some cases, this will mean that you should
                    write an actual conclusion sentence.
                </p>
            </li>
        </dl>
        Each exercise will be scored out of 4 points, one for each of these categories. A zero in
        some category doesn't really mean 0%, it just means I felt there was significant room for
        improvement and you coudl try again.
    </p>

    <paragraphs xml:id="written1">
        <title>Written HW 1</title>
        <p>
            This assignment has six exercises from the textbook.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 3.9 #4.</alert>
            The table shows the population of Nepal (in millions) as of June 30 of the given
            year. Use a linear approximation to estimate the population at midyear in 1989. Use
            another linear approximation to predict the population in 2010.
        </p>
        <tabular>
            <row>
                <cell><m>t</m></cell>
                <cell>1985</cell>
                <cell>1990</cell>
                <cell>1995</cell>
                <cell>2000</cell>
                <cell>2005</cell>
            </row>
            <row>
                <cell><m>N(t)</m></cell>
                <cell>17.04</cell>
                <cell>19.33</cell>
                <cell>21.91</cell>
                <cell>24.70</cell>
                <cell>27.68</cell>
            </row>
        </tabular>
        <p>
            Notes. Don't miss that there are two parts to this exercise. For each part, your
            write-up should include a formula for a linear function that approximates
            <m>N(t)</m>, and then use that formula at an appropriate value for <m>t</m>. You
            should properly interpret the result.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 3.9 #10.</alert>
            Find the linear approximation of the function <m>g(x)=\sqrt[3]{1+x}</m> at
            <m>a=0</m> and use it to approximate the numbers <m>\sqrt[3]{0.95}</m> and
            <m>\sqrt[3]{1.1}</m>. Illustrate by graphing <m>g</m> and the tangent line.
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. For the first two parts, it is up to you to determine the appropriate value
            for <m>x</m>. For the illustration, provide either an <em>accurate</em> hand-drawn
            copy of computer-generated graphs, or insert an actual computer-generated image into
            your write-up.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 4.7 #1.</alert>
            The figure shos the graph of a function <m>f</m>. Suppose that Newton's method is
            used to approximate the root <m>r</m> of the equation <m>f(x)=0</m> with initial
            approximation <m>x_1=1</m>.
            <ol marker="a.">
                <li>
                    <p>
                        Draw the thangent lines that are used to find <m>x_2</m> and <m>x_3</m>,
                        and extimate the numerical values of <m>x_2</m> and <m>x_3</m>.
                    </p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>
                        Would <m>x_1=5</m> be a better first approximation? Explain.
                    </p>
                </li>
            </ol>
            [You will have to find the figure in the textbook.]
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. You should hand-draw the figure in your write-up. If possible, trace it from
            the book or a screen (but don't damage your screen). Then use a straight-edge as you
            hand-draw the relevant lines. In part (b), give a convincing explanation as to why
            or why not <m>x_1=5</m> would make a better first approxiation. This may require
            you to make an additional graph.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 4.7 #27.</alert>
            Explain why Newton's method fails when applied to the equation <m>\sqrt[3]{x}=0</m>
            with any intial approximation <m>x_1\neq0</m>. Illustrate your explanation with a
            sketch.
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. Give a convincing explanation.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 7.1 #6.</alert>
            <ol marker="a.">
                <li>
                    <p>
                        Show that every member of the family of functions <m>y=(\ln x+C)/x</m>
                        is a solution to the differential equation <m>x^2y'+xy=1</m>.
                    </p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>
                        Illustrate part (a) by graphing several members of the family of
                        solutions on a common screen.
                    </p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>
                        Find a solution of the differential equation that satisfies the initial
                        condition <m>y(1)=2</m>.
                    </p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>
                        Find a solution of the differential equation that satisfies the initial
                        condition <m>y(2)=1</m>.
                    </p>
                </li>
            </ol>
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. Part (a): this should be a clear presentation that a generic member of that
            family would work when substituted into that differential equation. Part (b):
            provide either an <em>accurate</em> hand-drawn copy of computer-generated graphs, or
            insert an actual computer-generated image into your write-up. Parts (c) and (d):
            inlcude whatever algebra steps you take to find the particular solutions these parts
            ask for.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 7.1 #11.</alert>
            Explain why the functions with the given graphs <em>can't</em> be solutions of the
            differential equation
            <me>\frac{dy}{dt}=e^t(y-1)^2</me>
            [You will have to find the two figures in the textbook.]
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. For each graph, there are at least two reasons that are reasonable to show.
            Consider when various quantities would be negative, zero, or positive in both the
            context of the equation and of the graph. You could also consider concavity.
        </p>
    </paragraphs>
    <paragraphs xml:id="written2">
        <title>Written HW 2</title>
        <p>
            This assignment has four exercises from the textbook.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 7.2 #18.</alert>
            Make a rough sketch of a direction field for the autonomous differential equation
            <m>y'=f(y)</m>, where the graph of <m>f</m> is as shown. How does the limiting behavior
            of solutions depend on the value of <m>y(0)</m>?
        </p>
        <p>
            [You will have to find the graph image in the textbook.]
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. The graph here is <em>not</em> a graph of <m>y(t)</m>. What you are doing here is
            working with the differential equation <m>y'=f(y)</m>, but you are not given a formula
            for the right side of that differential equation. Instead, you have this graph. For
            example, the graph shows that when <m>y=0</m>, then <m>f(y)</m> is some relatively large
            positive number. So in turn, <m>y'</m> would be a relatively large positive number. So
            on a graph of <m>y(t)</m>, if <m>y=0</m>, then the slope of <m>y(t)</m> at that location
            would be relatively large and positive. This has described how to draw slope field hairs
            all along the <m>t</m>-axis, which is where <m>y=0</m>. For the last part of the
            exercise, if you have a graph of <m>y(t)</m>, there are five regions on the
            <m>y</m>-axis for what the value of <m>y(0)</m> could be. You are being asked to
            describe the long-term consequences for <m>y(t)</m> as <m>t\to\infty</m>, depending on
            which region <m>y(0)</m> is in.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 7.2 #20.</alert>
            A direction field for a differential equation is shown. Draw, with a ruler, the graphs
            of the Euler approximations to the solution currve that passes through the origin. Use
            step sizes <m>h=1</m> and <m>h=0.5</m>. Will the Euler estimates be under-estimates or
            over-estimates? Explain.
        </p>
        <p>
            [You will have to find the graph image in the textbook.]
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. It is important to accurately present this graph in your response. So I recommend
            that you take a picture of the image, print it, and then draw on top of that. Also at
            the end, be sure you are explaining why you feel the estimates are under-estimates or
            over-estimates.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 7.3 #43.</alert>
            A glucose solution is administered intrevenously into the bloodstream at a constant rate
            <m>r</m>. As the glucose is added, it is converted into other substances and removed
            from the bloodstream at a rate that is proportional to the concentration at that time.
            Thus a model for the concentration <m>C=C(t)</m> of the glucose solution in the
            bloodstream is
            <me>\frac{dC}{dt}=r-kC</me>
            where <m>k</m> is a positive constant.
            <ol marker="a.">
                <li>
                    <p>
                        Suppose that the concentration at time <m>t=0</m> is <m>C_0</m>. Determine
                        the concentration at any time <m>t</m> by solving the differential equation.
                    </p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>
                        Assuming that <m>C_0\lt r/k</m>, find <m>\lim_{t\to\infty}C(t)</m> and
                        interpret your answer.
                    </p>
                </li>
            </ol>
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. Keep in mind that <m>r</m> and <m>k</m> are constants here. <m>C</m> changes over
            time. You can solve this separable differential equation in the usual way with some
            algebra rearrangement, then integrating, and then isolating <m>C</m>.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 7.3 #49.</alert>
            When a raindrop falls, it increases in size and so its mass at time <m>t</m> is a
            function of <m>t</m>, namely <m>m(t)</m>. The rate of growth of the mass is <m>km(t)</m>
            for some positive constant <m>k</m>. When we apply Newton's Law of Motion to the
            raindrop, we get <m>(mv)'=gm</m>, where <m>v</m> is the velocity of the raindrop
            (directed downward) and <m>g</m> is the acceleration due to gravity. The <term>terminal
            velocity</term> of the raindrop is <m>\lim_{t\to\infty}v(t)</m>. Find an expression for
            the terminal velocity in terms of <m>g</m> and <m>k</m>.
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. This is actually a multipart exercise. Several things could be done in order to
            reach the final goal of having that expression for the terminal velocity. The following
            is <em>one</em> outline for solving this.
            <ol marker="a.">
                <li>
                    <p>
                        <q>The rate of growth of the mass is <m>km(t)</m> for some positive constant
                        <m>k</m></q> is already a small differential equation exercise. You can
                        solve the differential equation here to find an explicit formula for
                        <m>m(t)</m>.
                    </p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>
                        Physics (that you don't need to understand if you haven't heard of it
                        before) is saying that next, <m>(mv)'=gm</m>. In that equation, <m>g</m> is
                        a positive constant (roughly <quantity><mag>9.8</mag><unit base="meter"/>
                        <per base="second" exp="2"/></quantity>), but both <m>m</m> and <m>v</m>
                        change over time. Well, you already found an explicit formula for
                        <m>m(t)</m>, so substitute that in. Then execute the <q>prime</q> from the
                        differential equation, applyng the product rule and chain rule as needed.
                        After simplifying, this should leave you with a pretty <q>small</q>
                        differential equation for <m>v</m> with respect to <m>t</m>.
                    </p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>
                        You can solve this differential equation and have an explicit formula for
                        <m>v(t)</m>. You may need to remember that in this context, <m>g</m> is a
                        <em>positive</em> number.
                    </p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>
                        Now that you have an explicit formula for <m>v(t)</m>, you can take its
                        limit as <m>t\to\infty</m>.
                    </p>
                </li>
            </ol>
        </p>
    </paragraphs>
    <paragraphs xml:id="written3">
        <title>Written HW 3</title>
        <p>
            This assignment has six exercises from the textbook.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 7.5 #1.</alert>
            Suppose that a population develops according to the logistic equation
            <m>\frac{dP}{dt}=0.05P-0.0005P^2</m> where <m>t</m> is measured in weeks.
            <ol marker="a.">
                <li>
                    <p>
                        What is the carrying capacity? What is the value of <m>k</m>?
                    </p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>
                        A direction field for this equation is shown. Where are the slopes close to
                        <m>0</m>? Where are they largest? Which solutions are increasing? Which
                        solutions are decreasing?
                    </p>
                    <p>
                        [You will have to find the graph image in the textbook.]
                    </p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>
                        Use the direction field to sketch solutions for initial populations of
                        <m>20</m>, <m>40</m>, <m>60</m>, <m>80</m>, <m>120</m>, and <m>140</m>.
                        What do these solutions have in common? How do they differ? Which solutions
                        have inflection points? At what population levels do they occur?
                    </p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>
                        What are the equilibrium solutions? How are the other solutions related to
                        these solutions?
                    </p>
                </li>
            </ol>
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. This differential equation is not presented in the canonical form for a logistic
            equation. But you can use factoring to convert it into that form.
        </p>
        <p>
            In part (c), the last question is asking at what population levels do the
            <em>inflection points</em> occur.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 7.5 #11.</alert>
            <ol marker="a">
                <li>
                    <p>
                        Show that if <m>P</m> satisfies the logistic equation, then
                        <me>\frac{d^2P}{dt^2}=k^2P\left(1-\frac{P}{M}\right)\left(1-\frac{2P}{M}\right)</me>
                    </p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>
                        Deduce that the population grows fastes when it reaches half its carrying
                        capacity.
                    </p>
                </li>
            </ol>
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. Start with the logistic differential euqation and just see what happens when you
            apply <m>\frac{d}{dt}</m> to each side. You will have to use the product rule and the
            chain rule (since you will be differentiating with respect to <m>t</m>, but the right
            side only has <m>P</m> in it). You should keep an eye out for common factors that you
            can factor out, and not multiply things out too much.
        </p>
        <p>
            For the second part, recall that a function reaches a maximal slope where the second
            derivative is zero and the second derivative is transitioning from positive to negative.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 8.1 #19.</alert>
            Determine whether the sequence <m>a_n=\frac{(-1)^{n-1}n}{n^2+1}</m> converges or
            diverges. If it converges, find the limit.
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. The function <m>f(x)=\frac{(-1)^{x-1}x}{x^2+1}</m> does not make sense for most
            real numbers <m>x</m>, because you can't raise <m>-1</m> to arbitrary powers like
            <m>\frac12</m>. So you cannot use certain tools like l'Hospital's Rule to analyze this
            sequence. You will have to use other tools from the section.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 8.1 #29.</alert>
            Determine whether the sequence <m>\left\{\frac{(2n-1)!}{(2n+1)!}\right\}</m> converges
            or diverges. If it converges, find the limit.
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. This sequence is only defined for non-negative integers <m>n</m>. So you cannot
            use certain tools like l'Hospital's Rule to analyze this sequence. You will have to use
            other tools from the section.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 8.1 #40.</alert>
            Use a graph of the sequence to decide whether the sequence is convergent or divergent.
            If the sequence is convergent, guess the value of the limit from the graph and then
            prove your guess.
            <me>a_n=\frac{1\cdot3\cdot5\cdot\cdots\cdot(2n-1)}{(2n)^n}</me>
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. You should include a plot. It could be hand-plotted or computer-generated. To
            <q>prove your guess</q>, see Example 9 from the textbook. This exercise is similar.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 8.1 #44.</alert>
            Find the first 40 terms of the sequence defined by
            <me>a_{n+1}=\begin{cases}\frac12a_n&amp;\text{if }a_n\text{ is an even number}\\3a_n+1&amp;\text{if }a_n\text{ is an odd number}\end{cases}</me>
            and <m>a_1=11</m>. Do the same if <m>a_1=25</m>. Make a conjecture about this type of
            sequence.
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. Think slowly and carefully when you start working out the numbers in this
            sequence. For getting started, <m>a_1=11</m>, which is an odd number. So to find
            <m>a_2</m>, you use the <m>3a_n+1</m> formula, and you find <m>a_2=34</m>.
        </p>
    </paragraphs>
    <paragraphs xml:id="written4">
        <title>Written HW 4</title>
        <p>
            This assignment has six exercises from the textbook.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 8.2 #5.</alert>
            Find at least <m>10</m> partial sums of the series
            <me>
                \sum_{n=1}^{\infty}\frac{n}{\sqrt{n^2+4}}
            </me>
            Graph both the sequence of terms and the sequence of partial sums on the same plot. Does
            it appear that the series is convergent or divergent? If it is convergent, find the sum.
            If it is divergent, explain why.
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. You may use a computer graphing tool if you would like to, for making the plot.
            If you make it by hand, make a precise plot. For the second part of the question, you
            are expected to either <em>prove</em> that the series converges to some specific number
            or <em>prove</em> that it is divergent. The plot is a helpful start, but proves nothing.
            You will only earn the point for <q>convincing</q> if you make a convincing argument
            here.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 8.2 #33.</alert>
            Determine whether the series
            <me>
                \sum_{n=1}^{\infty}\frac{3}{n(n+3)}
            </me>
            is convergent or divergent by expressing <m>s_n</m> as a telescoping sum (as in Example
            6). If it is convergent, find its sum.
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. Find the helpful way to rewrite <m>\frac{3}{n(n+3)}</m> as
            <m>\frac{\text{something}}{n}+\frac{\text{something else}}{n+3}</m>. After that, if you
            need help seeing what happens next, write out the first five or six partial sums. Write
            them out <em>without</em> adding up the fractions. Look for cancellation instead.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 8.2 #44.</alert>
            We have seen that the harmonic series is a divergent series whose terms approach
            <m>0</m>. Show that
            <me>
                \sum_{n=1}^{\infty}\ln\left(1+\frac{1}{n}\right)
            </me>
            is another series with this property.
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. There is a logarithm rule that says <m>\ln(a)+\ln(b)=\ln(ab)</m>. Also, it may
            help to see that <m>1+\frac{1}{n}=\frac{n+1}{n}</m>. What happens when you have the
            <m>n</m>th partial sum of this series, and you apply these observations? Can you show
            that the <m>n</m>th partial sum will grow without bound?
        </p>
        <p>
            Don't forget to also show that the terms of this series approach <m>0</m>.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 8.2 #52 parts (a) and (b).</alert>
            A certain ball has the property that each time it falls from a height <m>h</m> onto a
            hard, level surface, it rebounds to a height <m>rh</m> where <m>0\lt r\lt 1</m>.
            Suppose that the ball is dropped from an initial height of <m>H</m> meters.
            <ol marker="a.">
                <li>
                    <p>
                        Assuming that the ball continues to bounce indefinitely, find the total
                        distance that it travels.
                    </p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>
                        Calculate the total time that the ball travels. (Use the fact that the ball
                        falls <m>\frac12gt^2</m> meters in <m>t</m> seconds. On earth, <m>g</m> is
                        about <m>9.8\,\frac{\text{m}}{\text{s}^2}</m>.)
                    </p>
                </li>
            </ol>
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes.
            <ol marker="a.">
                <li>
                    <p>
                        On its first drop, it falls <m>H</m> meters. After that, the ball goes up
                        and comes down, repeatedly. So each bounce adds a certain amount of distance
                        traveled. Write this all down as a series, and it should be a geometric
                        series that you can work with.
                    </p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>
                        You know how much distance the ball falls on the second half of its bounce.
                        So you can solve for <m>t</m> to know how much time passes during the second
                        half of its bounce. And you can double that for the full time of its bounce.
                        You can write all this down to give a total amount of time the ball is
                        bouncing, and it should be a geometric series you can work with. Of course,
                        the initial drop is a bit different, so don't include that in your sum.
                    </p>
                </li>
            </ol>
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 8.2 #56</alert>
            Graph the curves <m>y=x^n</m>, <m>0\leq x\leq1</m>, for <m>n=0,1,2,3,4,\ldots</m> on a
            common set of axes. By finding the areas between successive curves, give a geometric
            demonstration of the fact, shown in Example 6, that
            <me>\sum_{n=1}^{\infty}\frac{1}{n(n+1)}=1</me>
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. The graphs should only be from <m>x=0</m> to <m>x=1</m>. To find the area between
            successive curves, use your integral skills. The result for this should be an
            expression that depends on <m>n</m>, that you can simplify to a single rational
            expression. Make sure that you explain to the reader what the purpose of this is: that
            you are showing a visual reason why <m>\sum_{n=1}^{\infty}\frac{1}{n(n+1)}=1</m>.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 8.2 #59</alert>
            What is wrong with the following calculation?
            <md>
                <mrow>0\amp=0+0+0+\cdots</mrow>
                <mrow>\amp=(1-1)+(1-1)+(1-1)+\cdots</mrow>
                <mrow>\amp=1-1+1-1+1-1+\cdots</mrow>
                <mrow>\amp=1+(-1+1)+(-1+1)+(-1+1)+\cdots</mrow>
                <mrow>\amp=1+0+0+0+\cdots=1</mrow>
            </md>
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. Of course the final result that would say <m>0=1</m> is wrong. What exaclty
            happens along the way with these steps, that makes the argument wrong? You should think
            about each line with <m>\cdots</m> as an infinite series, and from that perspective it
            is more clear what goes wrong.
        </p>
    </paragraphs>
    <paragraphs xml:id="written5">
        <title>Written HW 5</title>
        <p>
            This assignment has four exercises from the textbook.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 8.3 #1.</alert>
            Draw a picture to show that
            <me>\sum_{n=2}^{\infty}\frac{1}{n^{1.3}}\lt\int_1^{\infty}\frac{1}{x^{1.3}}\,dx</me>
            What can you conclude about the series?
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. You should make a good effort to make the picture accurate, within the
            limitations of human drawing skills. Since you will want the <m>x</m>-axis to go 
            pretty far (like to at least <m>x=5</m> if not further) but the <m>y</m>-axis only needs
            to go up to a little past <m>1</m>, it will help if you use different scales on your
            axes. 
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 8.3 #14.</alert>
            Determine whether the series is convergent or divergent.
            <me>1+\frac{1}{2\sqrt{2}}+\frac{1}{3\sqrt{3}}+\frac{1}{4\sqrt{4}}+\frac{1}{5\sqrt{5}}+\cdots</me>
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. Ideally you are supposed to figure out the following for yourself, but this is a
            series where you can pply the Integral Test...
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 8.3 #39.</alert>
            <ol marker="a.">
                <li>
                    <p>
                        Use a graph of <m>y=1/x</m> to show that if <m>s_n</m> is the <m>n</m>th
                        partial sum of the harmonic series, then <me>s_n\leq1+\ln(n)</me>
                    </p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>
                        The harmonic series diverges, but very slowly. Use part (a) to show that the
                        sum of the first million terms is less than <m>15</m> and the sum of the
                        first billion terms is less than <m>22</m>.
                    </p>
                </li>
            </ol>
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. The purpose of this exercise is to look into how slowly the harmonic series
            diverges. Ask yourself at the end of this if you appreciate how even after adding a
            billion terms from this series together, how that partial sum being less than <m>22</m>
            reveals how slowly the partial sums approach infinity.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 8.3 #44.</alert>
            Find all positive values of <m>b</m> for which the series
            <m>\sum_{n=1}^{\infty}b^{\ln n}</m> converges.
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. This series is <m>b^{\ln(1)}+b^{\ln(2)}+b^{\ln(3)}+\cdots</m>. First of all, you
            can use the Test for Divergence to rule out some values of <m>b</m>. Once you have done
            that, you should be able to use the Integral Test. There is a way that you can rewrite
            <m>b^{\ln(n)}</m> that will help you do the integral.
        </p>
    </paragraphs>
    <paragraphs xml:id="written6">
        <title>Written HW 6</title>
        <p>
            This assignment has seven exercises from the textbook.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 8.3 #10.</alert>
            Use the Comparison Test to determine whether the series is convergent or divergent.
            <me>\sum_{n=2}^{\infty}\frac{n^3}{n^4-1}</me>
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. Your write-up should convince your reader that you are correctly appling the
            Comparison Test. You should acknowledge that the conditions have been met to even try
            to use the Comparison Test. When you comparre this series with another series, you
            should make sure your reader understands why that other series converges or diverges.
            It could be as simple as citing some small facto about it, or it could be a more
            involved explanation.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 8.3 #29.</alert>
            Determine whether the series is convergent or divergent.
            <me>\sum_{n=1}^{\infty}\sin\left(\frac{1}{n}\right)</me>
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. Ideally you are supposed to explore this series and determine which tools are
            appropriate and helpful. But this series can be successfully studied with either the
            Limit Comparison Test (my recommendation) or with the Comparison Test.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 8.3 #33.</alert>
            <ol marker="a.">
                <li>
                    <p>
                        Use the sum of the first <m>10</m> terms to estimate the sum of the series
                        <m>\sum_{n=1}^{\infty}1/n^2</m>. How good is this estimate?
                    </p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>
                        Improve the estimate using (4) with <m>n=10</m>.

                    </p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>
                        Find a value of <m>n</m> that will ensure that the error in the
                        approximation <m>s\approx s_n</m> is less than <m>0.001</m>m>.
                    </p>
                </li>
            </ol>
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. Part (a) is asking you to use the boxed inequality labeled <q>3</q> in the
            section to understand how far off <m>s_{10}</m> is from the full sum <m>s</m>. Part (b)
            is asking you to use the boxed inequality labeled <q>4</q> in the section, so that you
            are bounding the full sum in between an under-estimate and an over-estimate.
        </p>
        <p>
            For part (c), note that you want <m>R_n\lt0.001</m>. You know that
            <m>R_n\lt\int_n^{\infty}f(x)\,dx</m>, so if you can make it so that
            <m>\int_n^{\infty}f(x)\,dx\ln0.001</m>, mission acomplished.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 8.4 #6.</alert>
            Test the series for convergence or divergence.
            <m>\sum_{n=1}^{\infty}\frac{(-1)^{n-1}}{\ln(n+4)}</m>
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. Ideally you are supposed to explore this series and determine which tools are
            appropriate and helpful. But this series can be successfully studied with the
            Alternating Series Test. You <em>must</em> persuade your reader that the series meets
            the conditions to use the Alternating Series Test in the first place.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 8.4 #12.</alert>
            Calculate the first <m>10</m> partial sums of the series
            <m>\sum_{n=1}^{\infty}\frac{(-1)^{n-1}}{n^3}</m>
            and graph both the sequence of terms and the sequence of partial sums on the same
            screen. Estimate the error in using the <m>10</m>th partial sum to approximate the total
            sum.
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. The last part of this exercise is asking you to use the <q>Alternating Series
            Estimation Theorem</q> from the section.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 8.4 #30.</alert>
            Determine whether the series is absolutely convergent.
            <m>\sum_{n=1}^{\infty}\frac{\sin(4n)}{4^n}</m>
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. You could try to use the Ratio Test, but the limit from that attempt does not
            exist. Instead, you should directly explore
            <m>\sum_{n=1}^{\infty}\left\lvert a_n\right\rvert</m> and see what you find. You may
            need to use an earlier tool to establish whether or not
            <m>\sum_{n=1}^{\infty}\left\lvert a_n\right\rvert</m> converges.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 8.4 #32.</alert>
            Determine whether the series is absolutely convergent.
            <m>\sum_{n=1}^{\infty}\frac{(-2)^nn!}{(2n)!}</m>
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. This is an excellent series to use the Ratio Test with. You will have to
            carefully simplify some expressions that have factorials in them. If simplified
            correctly, there will be no more factorials
        </p>
    </paragraphs>
    <paragraphs xml:id="written7">
        <title>Written HW 7</title>
        <p>
            This assignment has six exercises from the textbook.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 8.5 #28.</alert>
            Graph the first several partial sums <m>s_n(x)</m> of the series
            <m>\sum_{n=0}^{\infty}x^n</m>, together with the sum function <m>f(x)=1/(1-x)</m>, on a
            common screen. On what interval do these partial sums appear to be converging to
            <m>f(x)</m>?
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. Your response needs to include computer-generated graphs. You could copy-paste
            them into a digital document, or print them out separately.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 8.5 #33.</alert>
            Suppose the series <m>\sum c_nx^n</m> has radius of convergence <m>2</m> and the series
            <m>\sum d_nx^n</m> has radius of convergence <m>3</m>. What is the radius of convergence
            of the series <m>\sum(c_n+d_n)x^n</m>?
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. Do all the series here have the same center? First imagine some <m>x</m>-value
            that is within <m>2</m> of that center. Would <m>\sum(c_n+d_n)x^n</m> converge?
            What about if <m>x</m> is more than <m>3</m> away from that center? What if it is
            in between <m>2</m> and <m>3</m> units away?
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 8.5 #35.</alert>
            Is it possible to find a power series whose interval of convergence is
            <m>[0,\infty)</m>? Explain.
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. You must either provide an example of a power series where you can convince your
            reader that its interval of convergence is <m>[0,\infty)</m>, or you must write a
            convincing argument to your reader that this is impossible.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 8.6 #2.</alert>
            Suppose you know that the series <m>\sum_{n=0}^{\infty}b_nx^n</m> converges for
            <m>|x|\lt2</m>. What can you say about the following series? Why?
            <me>\sum_{n=0}^{\infty}\frac{b_n}{n+1}x^{n+1}</me>
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. Think about how the first series can be used to obtain the second.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 8.6 #20.</alert>
            Find a power series representation for <m>f(x)=\ln\left(x^2+4\right)</m>, and graph
            <m>f</m> and several partial sums <m>s_n(x)</m> on the same screen. What happens as
            <m>n</m> increases?
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. Your response needs to include computer-generated graphs. You could copy-paste
            them into a digital document, or print them out separately.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 8.6 #35.</alert>
            <ol marker="a.">
                <li>
                    <p>
                        Show that the function <me>f(x)=\sum_{n=0}^{\infty}\frac{x^n}{n!}</me> is a
                        solution of the differential equation <me>f'(x)=f(x)</me>.
                    </p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>
                        Show that <m>f(x)=e^x</m>.
                    </p>
                </li>
            </ol>
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. This is an exercise from section 8.6, before we know about Maclaurin/Taylor
            series. You are not permitted to simply cite the Maclaurin series for <m>e^x</m> to
            answer this. Instead, use the series, take its derivative, and make it clear to the
            reader that the derivative and the original series are the same thing. For part (b),
            remember from Chapter 7 how to solve the differetial equation <m>y'=y</m>. It is a
            separable equation. Also you know the initial value of the given series is <m>1</m>,
            because
            <m>f(0)=\left.\sum_{n=0}^{\infty}\frac{x^n}{n!}\right|_{x=0}=\left.1+x+\cdots\right|_{x=0}=1</m>. 
        </p>
    </paragraphs>
    <paragraphs xml:id="written8">
        <title>Written HW 8</title>
        <p>
            This assignment has four exercises from the textbook.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 8.7 #2.</alert>
            The graph of <m>f</m> is shown. [You will have to find the figure in the textbook.]
            <ol marker="a.">
                <li>
                    <p>
                        Explain why the series
                        <me>
                            1.6-0.8(x-1)+0.4(x-1)^2-0.1(x-1)^3+\cdots
                        </me>
                        is <em>not</em> the Taylor series of <m>f</m> centered at <m>1</m>.
                    </p>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <p>
                        Explain why the series
                        <me>
                            2.8+0.5(x-2)+1.5(x-2)^2-0.1(x-2)^3+\cdots
                        </me>
                        is <em>not</em> the Taylor series of <m>f</m> centered at <m>2</m>.
                    </p>
                </li>
            </ol>
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. To have a write-up that makes sense to a reader, you must include the given
            graph.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 8.7 #40.</alert>
            Use the Maclaurin series for <m>sin(x)</m> to complute <m>\sin 3^\circ</m> correct to
            five decimal places.
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. In radians, <m>3^\circ</m> is <m>3\cdot\frac{\pi}{180}=\frac{\pi}{60}</m>.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 8.8 #6.</alert>
            Find the Taylor polynomial <m>T_3(x)</m> for the function <m>f(x)=\frac{\ln x}{x}</m>
            at the number <m>a=1</m>. Graph <m>f</m> and <m>T_3</m> on the same screen.
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. Of course your write-up should include the computer-generated graph. The
            exercise does not ask for this, but it would be nice for you to comment about for which
            <m>x</m> would <m>f(x)\approx T_3(x)</m> be a good approximation.
        </p>
        <p>
            <alert>Section 8.8 #24.</alert>
            Use the Alternating Series Estimation Theorem or Taylor's Inequality to estimate the
            range of values of <m>x</m> for which <m>\cos(x)\approx1-\frac{x^2}{2}+\frac{x^4}{24}</m>
            is accurate to within <m>0.005</m>.
        </p>
        <p>
            Notes. While the polynomial here may look like <m>T_4</m>, it is better if you think of
            it as <m>T_5</m>, with a <m>0x^5</m> tacked on to the end. Then if you use Taylor's
            Inequality, you will get the same error bound as if you used the Alternating Series
            Estimation Theorem.
        </p>
    </paragraphs>
</section>
