<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!-- This file is part of Alex Jordan's syllabus -->
   
<section xml:id="section-written-assignments" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
    <title>Written Assignments</title>

    <p>As the term progresses, more written assignements will be added to the list here. These must be turned in no later than their posted due dates. Written assignments are each worth <quantity><mag>3</mag><unit base="percent"/></quantity> of your final grade, and there will be seven in total. That means they are worth <quantity><mag>21</mag><unit base="percent"/></quantity> in total, so you cannot expect to pass this course unless you are turning these assignments in. These are where you will get to show me your mathematical writing skills and work on your ability to create a convincing logical argument.</p>

    <p>The most important thing to understand about your written homework is that <alert>you are not merely finding and giving answers.</alert> You are <em>explaining to someone what the problem was, how you handled it, and summarizing the results.</em>  In general, your write-ups should respect these <q>five C's</q>:</p>

    <ol>
        <li><p>Clarity. Am I able to read your work? Is your writing legible? Have you written complete sentences that make sense, where appropriate? If you have charts, graphs, and mathematical expressions, have you clearly indicated what they represent? Generally, any graphs need their axes labeled with regularly spaced tick marks, and they need some kind of overall title. If something about your write-up causes me to pause and wonder what you mean, you will lose clarity points.</p>
        </li>
        <li><p>Correctness. Are your numerical answers and conclusions accurate? Often you can check that your numbers are correct by substituting numbers back into earlier equations. Also, by asking yourself if the numbers that you find make sense in the context of the problem. It's not a bad idea to include these checks with your work.</p>
        </li>
        <li><p>Conciseness. Have you rambled on with extra content that is not relevant to solving the problem? This is distracting and hurts the overall ability of your write-up to communicate effectively.</p>
        </li>
        <li><p>self-Containment. The response to the question that you submit should make it clear what the original question was. Put yourself in the shoes of another student from the class who does not have the original homework assignment in front of them. Would they be able to understand what you are talking about? At a minimum, this means that <alert>you must give an introduction of some kind that lets your reader know what you are about to investigate</alert>. Also, include any and all charts, graphs, and mathematical expressions that were given in the problem, and explain their meaning, even if you do so merely with labels.</p>
        </li>
        <li><p>Conclusions. Some problems come with context (<q>word problems</q>). When writing your final answer to such a question, you need to put that answer in its full context with a conclusion statement that is a complete English sentence. As an example, writing <q><m>x=70</m></q> or <q>He needs <dollar/>70</q> will not be good enough if there is more context to the problem. Instead, something like <q>Dmitri needs <dollar/>70 in order to purchase a new lawnmower</q> is a conclusion statement with all of the context in it. For problems without context, conclusion statements like <q>So the domain of <m>f</m> is <m>[0,\infty)</m>.</q> are acceptable.</p>
        </li>
    </ol>

    <dl>
        <li xml:id="written1">
            <title>Written HW 1</title>
            <p>Due Tuesday June 28</p>
            <ul> 
                <li><p>Section 8.1 <hash />1. It is too easy to answer these questions informally. To receive full credit, explain in precise mathematical terms what these things mean.</p>
                </li>
                <li><p>Section 8.1 <hash />44. The sequence defined here is a recursive sequence. Often with this problem, students misunderstand the given formula. If you compute terms of this sequence and get non-integer values, then you are misunderstanding the formula and you should seek help.</p>
                    <p>At the end you are asked to make a conjecture. To do that, you must have completed the earlier parts of the problem first. And then you look at your results and see what you might guess about sequences like this.</p>
                </li>
                <li><p>Section 8.1 <hash />54. Consult example 13 before attempting this problem. If you have trouble with the induction argument, plan ahead to make time to meet with me to discuss it prior to the due date.</p>
                </li>
            </ul> 
        </li>
        <li xml:id="written2">
            <title>Written HW 2</title>
            <p>Due Tuesday July 5</p>
            <ul> 
                <li><p>Section 8.2 <hash />2.</p>
                </li>
                <li><p>Section 8.2 <hash />44. Hint: note that <m>1+\frac{1}{x}=\frac{x+1}{x}</m> and use logarithm rules to rewrite the expression. This series is a special kind of series we investigated.</p>
                </li>
                <li><p>Section 8.2 <hash />59. Understanding an example like this is very important to truly understand what the value of an infinite series really means. One of the lines here is nonsense.</p>
                </li>
            </ul> 
        </li>
        <li xml:id="written3">
            <title>Written HW 3</title>
            <p>Due Thursday July 7</p>
            <ul> 
                <li><p>Section 8.3 <hash />16. For full credit, clearly portray the given sequence in a way such that one of the various convergence tests applies, and then clearly show how that test applies and what the conclusion is. For whichever test you use, if that test has any conditions, you must fully establish that those conditions are met.</p>
                </li>
                <li><p>Section 8.3 <hash />24. For full credit, clearly portray the given sequence in a way such that one of the various convergence tests applies, and then clearly show how that test applies and what the conclusion is. For whichever test you use, if that test has any conditions, you must fully establish that those conditions are met.</p>
                </li>
                <li><p>Section 8.3 <hash />4. The <q>Why?</q> part of these questions are important to answer clearly.</p>
                </li>
            </ul> 
        </li>
        <li xml:id="written4">
            <title>Written HW 4</title>
            <p>Due Tuesday July 12</p>
            <ul> 
                <li><p>Section 8.4 <hash />8. For full credit, clearly portray the given sequence in a way such that one of the various convergence tests applies, and then clearly show how that test applies and what the conclusion is. For whichever test you use, if that test has any conditions, you must fully establish that those conditions are met.</p>
                </li>
                <li><p>Section 8.4 <hash />26. For full credit, clearly portray the given sequence in a way such that one of the various convergence tests applies, and then clearly show how that test applies and what the conclusion is. For whichever test you use, if that test has any conditions, you must fully establish that those conditions are met.</p>
                </li>
                <li><p>Section 8.4 <hash />30. For full credit, clearly portray the given sequence in a way such that one of the various convergence tests applies, and then clearly show how that test applies and what the conclusion is. For whichever test you use, if that test has any conditions, you must fully establish that those conditions are met.</p>
                </li>
            </ul> 
        </li>
        <li xml:id="written5">
            <title>Written HW 5</title>
            <p>Due Tuesday July 19</p>
            <ul> 
                <li><p>Section 8.5 <hash />10. If you find a finite radius of convergence, you are required to separately investigate the convergence status at each endpoint of the interval of convergence.</p>
                </li>
                <li><p>Section 8.5 <hash />20. If you find a finite radius of convergence, you are required to separately investigate the convergence status at each endpoint of the interval of convergence.</p>
                </li>
                <li><p>Section 8.5 <hash />26. Note that part (a) is the power series from the introduction with <m>x=1</m>. For each part, give a celar explanation <em>why</em> you are stating that the series converges or diverges.</p>
                </li>
            </ul> 
        </li>
        <li xml:id="written6">
            <title>Written HW 6</title>
            <p>Due Tuesday August 2</p>
            <ul> 
                <li><p>Section 8.6 <hash />14. Hint: recall that <me>\tan^{-1}\left(x^3\right)=\int_0^{x^3}\frac{1}{1+u^2}\,du\text{.}</me></p>
                </li>
                <li><p>Section 8.7 <hash />2.</p>
                </li>
                <li><p>Section 8.7 <hash />10. Follow the instructions and use the <em>definition</em> of the Maclaurin series, not the shortcut formulas for common functions.</p>
                </li>
            </ul> 
        </li>
        <li xml:id="written7">
            <title>Written HW 7</title>
            <p>Due Tuesday August 9</p>
            <ul> 
                <li><p>Section 9.3 <hash />45. Use the dot product method to find an angle that is covered in this seciton.</p>
                </li>
                <li><p>Section 9.4 <hash />24.</p>
                </li>
                <li><p>Section 9.5 <hash />30.</p>
                </li>
            </ul> 
        </li>
    </dl>
</section>
