<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!-- This file is part of Alex Jordan's syllabus -->
   
<section xml:id="section-expectations" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
    <title>Expectations</title>

    <p>MTH 111 is a technically demanding course which is paced steadily and introduces concepts that form the foundation of calculus.  The ideas are covered in a natural sequence, and if the student stays on top of the work load, they have every chance of success.  Topics will be discussed in class, with exercises that tune the technique and problems that reenforce understanding.</p>

    <p>At this level of learning, the student is responsible for ensuring their own understanding.  Questions are encouraged both during class and in office hours. Indeed, they are a significant part of the learning process.  All students are further encouraged to work together<mdash/>collaboration is an important part of any activity, and it is almost always beneficial for all involved.</p>

    <subsection>
        <title>Technology</title>
        <p>Part of this course involves teaching you how to use a graphing calculator such as a TI-84, TI-89 or Casio Classpad. You are <alert>required</alert> to have one and bring it to class everyday.</p>

        <p>You will also need Internet access for most of your homework. If you do not have Internet access at home, you can find it in PCC computer labs. Here is an example of what WeBWorK is like.</p>

        <exercise>
            <title>Multiply Powers</title>

            <webwork>
                <pg-macros>
                    <macro-file>contextLimitedPolynomial.pl</macro-file>
                </pg-macros>

                <setup>
                    <var name="$a">
                        <static>4</static>
                    </var>
                    <var name="$b">
                        <static>3</static>
                    </var>
                    <var name="$c">
                        <static>7</static>
                    </var>
                    <var name="$expression">
                        <static>x^4\cdot x^3</static>
                    </var>
                    <var name="$answer" category="formula">
                        <static>x^7</static>
                    </var>

                    <pg-code>
                        $a = 4;
                        $b = 3;
                        $c = $a + $b;
                        $expression = Formula("x^($a)*x^($b)");

                        Context("LimitedPolynomial-Strict");
                        # custom error message
                        Context()->{error}{msg}{"A variable can appear only once in each term of a polynomial"}
                            = "Your answer must be fully simplified";

                        $answer = Formula("x^($c)");
                        $product = $a*$b;
                        $evaluator = $answer->cmp()->withPostFilter(AnswerHints(
                            [Compute("x^($product)")] =>
                            "When multiplying terms with the same base, you do not multiply the exponents."));
                    </pg-code>
                </setup>

                <statement>
                    <p>Use the properties of exponents to simplify <m><var name="$expression" /></m>.</p>
                    <p><m><var name="$expression" />=</m><answer var="$answer" evaluator="$evaluator" width="8" /></p>
                </statement>

                <solution>
                    <p>We <em>add</em> the exponents as follows:</p>
                    <md>
                        <mrow><var name="$expression" />&amp;=x^{<var name="$a" />+<var name="$b" />}</mrow>
                        <mrow>&amp;=x^{<var name="$c" />}</mrow>
                    </md>
                </solution>
            </webwork>
        </exercise>

    </subsection>

</section>
