<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!-- This file is part of Alex Jordan's syllabus -->

<section xml:id="grades" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
    <title>Grades</title>

    <introduction>
        <p>
            General PCC Grading Guidelines are found at
            <url href="http://catalog.pcc.edu/handbook/g301-gradingguidelines/">catalog.pcc.edu/handbook/g301-gradingguidelines</url>.
        </p>
    </introduction>

    <paragraphs>
        <title>Class Prep Assignments</title>
        <p>
            Most class days you are supposed to come to class with class prep notes completed.
            Download and print the <url href="notes/MTH65_Lecture_Outlines-sections.pdf"><q>class prep</q> video lecture notes</url>.
            You will show these to me at some point during class.
            Then while you work on some warm-up exercises,
            I will look over your prep assignments and give you credit for them.
            Each one is worth 0.5% of your grade.
            There are 17 of these total,
            so all together they are worth 8.5% of your grade.
        </p>

        <p>
            If you miss class, you may bring the completed class prep assignment to me the next class session.
        </p>
    </paragraphs>

    <paragraphs>
        <title>In-class Group Work</title>
        <p>
            Most class days, you will work in small groups on a collection of exercises
            that go along with the lesson you prepared for.
            If you work on these diligently during class time with your partners,
            you will get credit for 0.5% of your final grade for each one
            (even if your group is not able to finish these in time).
            There are 17 of these, so in total these are worth 8.5% of your grade.
        </p>

        <p>
            If you miss class, you may bring a <em>fully completed</em> activity to me within one week
            and still get the 0.5% credit.
            It must be fully completed, not partially completed.
            The work must be shown, not just the answers.
        </p>

        <p>
            Blank group activities are available for download at <xref ref="section-calendar-mw" text="title"/> or <xref ref="section-calendar-uh" text="title"/>.
        </p>
    </paragraphs>

    <paragraphs>
        <title>Online Homework</title>
        <p>
            Most of your homework for this class is to be submitted online through the free program <webwork/>.
            For details, see <xref ref="section-webwork" text="type-global"/>.
            Collectively, all web assignments are worth 11% of your final grade.
            For every web assignment that you do not submit (or have a poor score for),
            I will <em>replace</em> that score with the score you get on your next exam.
        </p>
    </paragraphs>

    <paragraphs>
        <title>Exams</title>
        <p>
            Please refer to <xref ref="section-calendar-mw" text="title"/> or <xref ref="section-calendar-uh" text="title"/>
            for exam dates, and to <xref text="title" ref="section-exams"/> for details about what is covered on each exam.
            Exams 1, 2, and 3 are each worth 24%, of your grade.
        </p>
    </paragraphs>

</section>
