<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<section xml:id="section-weekly-routine">
  <title>Weekly Routine</title>
  <p>
    Typically, a week covers two sections from the textbook. We discuss one section the first class
    meeting, and the other on the second. You should read these textbook sections and watch the
    embedded videos. It is best if you do this reading and watching <em>before</em> our class
    meeting. That can make the class discussion more meaningful for you. The
    <xref ref="section-calendar" text="title"/> shows you which sections are covered which weeks.
  </p>
  <p>
    You have online homework assignments for these sections in <webwork/>. You access <webwork/>
    from our D2L course. The <webwork/> assignments are due Sunday nights at 10:00pm for full
    credit. They can still be worked on up until Tuesday nights at 10:00pm for reduced credit.
  </p>
  <p>
    Online homework can only help you learn so much. Some exercises require you to write an
    explanation in order to help you truly learn something. So we also have written exercises each
    week. These are given in D2L, in the weekly Content module. We will often begin discussing
    these in class. Your write-up for these should be turned in by the following Tuesday morning.
    (Either in class Monday, scanned and posted to D2L, or brought to my Tuesday morning office
    hours.)
  </p>
  <p>
    All work that you do outside of class, your peers and tutors may help you understand the
    exercises, but you may not have other people or computer tools effectively do the exercises for
    you. Homework exercises are supposed to teach you things, and you should view them as
    opportunities to learn, not as homework for a grade. Then you will be in great shape for our
    exams.
  </p>
  <p>
    Throughout the week, consider reaching out for help in the following ways:
    <ul>
      <li>
        <p>the <q>Ask a Question</q> Discussion area in D2L</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>
          contacting people from the class (if you don't have contact info, try using Connect,
          Classlist, in our D2L course)
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>free tutoring from PCC at
          <url href="https://pcc.edu/tutoring" visual="pcc.edu/tutoring"/></p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>contacting me in office hours or over email</p>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </p>
</section>
