<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<section xml:id="grades">
  <title>Grades</title>
  <p>
    General PCC Grading Guidelines are found at
    <url
      href="http://catalog.pcc.edu/handbook/g301-gradingguidelines/"
      visual="catalog.pcc.edu/handbook/g301-gradingguidelines"
      />.
  </p>
  <paragraphs>
    <title>Attendance (2%)</title>
    <p>
      To further encourage you to attend class, a part of your grade comes from attendance. You will
      be able to see your attendance record in D2L. If you have to miss a class meeting, contact me
      as soon as possible to see if I can offer you a way to make up the missed attendance credit.
      The main reason to attend class is indirect though. In class we have discussions that help you
      understand the topics better, and you have opportunities to make progress on your homework
      while I and your classmates are available.
    </p>
  </paragraphs>
  <paragraphs>
    <title>Online Homework (25%)</title>
    <p>
      You have online homework for each section using <webwork/>. See
      <xref ref="section-webwork" text="title"/> for details. The due date for each assignment is
      posted in <webwork/>. Usually, more than one section will be due at the same time. You should
      start working on a homework assignment soon after the class that is associated with that
      section of the book. But always read the textbook section before beginning <webwork/>.
    </p>
  </paragraphs>
  <paragraphs>
    <title>Worksheets (25%)</title>
    <p>
      Each week there is a worksheet. You will usually begin these worksheets in class, where you
      are encouraged to collaborate in small groups. They can be posted in D2L Assignmens up until
      the coming Sunday evening at 10:00pm. Later than that, they can only be turned in physically
      at the start of the next class meeting (Monday or Tuesday).
    </p>
  </paragraphs>
  <paragraphs>
    <title>Exams (16% + 16% + 16%)</title>
    <p>
      There are three exams. Each exam takes place in class, unless there are special circumstances.
    </p>
  </paragraphs>
  <paragraphs>
    <title>Exams Minimum</title>
    <p>
      <alert>Important:</alert> In order to pass the course, there is an additional requirement that
      you must pass at least one of the three exams with a 70% or higher. If you do not pass any of
      the exams, then the highest possible letter grade that you can end with is a D, even if your
      overall average is above 70%.
    </p>
    <p>
      In particular, if you do not pass the first two exams, then in order to pass the course you
      must pass the final exam.
    </p>
    <p>
      Similarly, in order to pass the course with a B, you must at least pass <em>two</em> of the
      three exams with a 70% or higher. If passing MTH 95 with at least a B is important for you,
      and if you do not pass the first exam, then you must pass both of the remaining exams.
    </p>
  </paragraphs>
  <paragraphs>
    <title>Grading Options</title>
    <p>
      Students are solely responsible for adding, dropping, or withdrawing from any class, as well
      as for selecting their desired grading option. Please review
      <url
        href="http://www.pcc.edu/enroll/registration/policies.html"
        visual="www.pcc.edu/enroll/registration/policies.html">
          PCC Registration Policy
      </url>
      for more information.
    </p>
  </paragraphs>
  <paragraphs>
    <title>Letter Grades</title>
    <p>
      Your letter grade will be assigned based on the weighted average of the items above.
    </p>
    <tabular>
      <col/>
      <col right="minor"/>
      <col/>
      <col/>
      <row header="yes">
        <cell colspan="2">Pass (P)</cell>
        <cell colspan="2">No Pass (N)</cell>
      </row>
      <row>
        <cell>90% and up</cell>
        <cell>A</cell>
        <cell>60% up to 70%</cell>
        <cell>D</cell>
      </row>
      <row>
        <cell>80% up to 90%</cell>
        <cell>B</cell>
        <cell>under 60%</cell>
        <cell>F</cell>
      </row>
      <row>
        <cell>70% up to 80%</cell>
        <cell>C</cell>
      </row>
    </tabular>
    <p>
      Except as described above, you must pass at least one exam to complete the course with a C or
      higher. And you must pass at least two exams to complete the course with a B or higher.
    </p>
  </paragraphs>
</section>
