<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<section xml:id="section-weekly-routine">
  <title>Weekly Routine</title>
  <p>
    This course has a (mostly) consistent weekly design.
  </p>
  <p>
    Your week begins by:
    <ul>
      <li>
        <p>
          Reading assigned sections from the textbook and trying the embedded <q>Checkpoint</q>
          exercises. I cannot verify that you do these things. All I can tell you is that the most
          successful students complete the reading before they come to class.
        </p>
        <p>
          The textbook has embedded video lessons, and you might prefer to watch those instead of
          reading. Either way, if you read/watch the lessons before class, our time together in the
          classroom will have more impact.
        </p>
      </li>
    </ul>
    Then you will:
    <ul>
      <li>
        <p>
          Attend class twice a week unless there is a holiday or other school closure. During class
          we will solidify the topics from that day's textbook sections. We will use conversation,
          learning activities, and practice exercises during these times.
        </p>
      </li>
    </ul>
    You have two forms of homework:
    <ul>
      <li>
        <p>
          Worksheets with exercises where you will write complete explanations and conclusions. We
          will often start these assignments in class, where you may collaborate in small groups.
          It's preferred that you scan your completed worksheets and post them to D2L as soon as you
          are done so that I can give you feedback quickly. If scanning and posting is too much of a
          burden, you may turn them in the first day of class the following week. But you will be
          receiving feedback quite late if you do this.
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>
          Online homework in <webwork/> that is automatically graded. You should try to complete
          these exercises on your own, but you are welcome to reach out to me or a tutor for help.
          These assignments are due Sunday evenings at 10:00.
        </p>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </p>
  <p>
    Throughout the week, consider reaching out for help in the following ways:
    <ul>
      <li>
        <p>
          spend time in PCC's tutoring centers:
          <url href="https://pcc.edu/tutoring" visual="pcc.edu/tutoring"/>
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>post to the <q>Ask a Question</q> Discussion area in D2L</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>use our class Discord server</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>contact me over email</p>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </p>
</section>
