<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!-- This file is part of Alex Jordan's syllabus -->

<section xml:id="grades" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <title>Grades</title>

  <p>
    General PCC Grading Guidelines are found at
    <url href="http://catalog.pcc.edu/handbook/g301-gradingguidelines/">catalog.pcc.edu/handbook/g301-gradingguidelines</url>.
  </p>

  <paragraphs>
    <title>Attendance/Engagement</title>
    <p>
      Attending and participating in the Zoom class sessions is a small factor in calculating your final grade.
      Collectively, these sessions are worth 4% of your final grade.
    </p>
    <p>
      If you miss a class session, you can still recover that part of your grade.
      All that you need to do is watch the class recording.
      Send me a message confirming that you did this, and I will update the record in D2L.
      In your message, please include the specific date of the class recording that you watched.
    </p>
  </paragraphs>

  <paragraphs>
    <title>Online Homework</title>
    <p>
      You have online homework for each section using <webwork/>.
      See <xref ref="section-webwork" text="title"/> for details.
      The due date for each assignment is posted in <webwork/>.
      It will always be Sunday evening at 10:00<pm/>.
      Usually, more than one section will be due at the same time.
      You should start working on these exercises soon after the corresponding class session
    </p>

    <p>
      Collectively, all the online homework is worth 18% of your final grade.
    </p>

    <p>
      After a due date, you may still work on the online homework and submit answers for 95% credit.
    </p>
  </paragraphs>

  <paragraphs>
    <title>Discussion Posts</title>
    <p>
      Each week you will make a graded discussion post in D2L, responding to some topic that is posted.
      Collectively, these are worth 10% of your grade.
    </p>
    <p>
      When you make a post, I will give you private feedback and a score from 0 to 3.
      If you score less than 3, you are invited to continue adding to your discsussion thread,
      improving your response. I will update your score and send you new private feedback.
      Eventually, you should reach a score of 3/3 on each discussion topic.
      Here is a rubric that I use to determine your score with each post:
    </p>
    <tabular valign="top" top="major" bottom="minor">
      <col/>
      <col width="80%"/>
      <row>
        <cell>3 points</cell>
        <cell>
          <p>
            Post is correct, relevant, well-written, and pertains to the appropriate module and textbook sections.
            Post contains proper spelling, punctuation and grammar.
            Post contains proper mathematical notation and vocabulary.
          </p>
        </cell>
      </row>
      <row>
        <cell>2 points</cell>
        <cell>
          <p>
            Post would be worth 3 points, but has one of the following issues:
            <ul>
              <li>mostly correct, but not entirely correct</li>
              <li>noteworthy spelling, punctuation, grammar issues</li>
              <li>does not use mathematical notation and vocabulary correctly</li>
              <li>does not use equation editor where appropriate</li>
            </ul>
          </p>
        </cell>
      </row>
      <row>
        <cell>1 point</cell>
        <cell>
          <p>
            Post needs significant editing or revision.
            May have more than one of the issues listed for 2 points.
            Or it may only have a kernel of correctness but is mostly incorrect.
          </p>
        </cell>
      </row>
      <row bottom="major">
        <cell>0 points</cell>
        <cell>
          <p>
            Post does not contain any correct work.
            Or post is not related to the correct topic.
          </p>
        </cell>
      </row>
    </tabular>

    <p>
      The <q>due dates</q> for these weekly discussions are Sunday at 10:00<pm/>.
      This is purely advisory to help you stay on track. If you post late,
      or improve your initial post later than the <q>due date</q>,
      it does not hurt your grade.
    </p>
  </paragraphs>

  <paragraphs>
    <title>Written Assignments</title>
    <p>
      Each week you have an assignment of exercises to write up, scan, and turn in through D2L.
      Usually, most or all of these exercises will come from the
      <url href="https://spot.pcc.edu/math/clm/">PCC Calculus Lab Manual</url>.
    </p>
    <p>
      Collectively, these assignments are worth 18% of your grade.
    </p>
    <p>
      The <q>due dates</q> for these assignments are Sunday at 10:00<pm/>.
      This is purely advisory to help you stay on track. If you turn them in late,
      it does not hurt your grade.
    </p>
    <p>
      Please note that these assignments will only be scored once.
      There is not an opportunity to improve your score once an assignment is graded.
      But you are welcome to bring a draft of your work to an office hour,
      where we can informally look it over together to catch any significant issues
      before you turn it in.
    </p>
  </paragraphs>

  <paragraphs xml:id="paragraphs-exams">
    <title>Exams</title>
    <p>
      There is a final exam during finals week. It is worth 18% of your grade.
      There are two midterm exams, each worth 16% of your grade.
    </p>
    <p>
      Please see the <xref ref="section-calendar" text="title"/> for dates.
    </p>
    <p>
      The format of the exams is not fully determined at this time.
      You will have modules in D2L devoted to each exam with information about them.
    </p>
  </paragraphs>

</section>
