<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!-- This file is part of Alex Jordan's syllabus -->

<section xml:id="grades" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <title>Grades</title>

  <introduction>
    <p>
      General PCC Grading Guidelines are found at
      <url href="http://catalog.pcc.edu/handbook/g301-gradingguidelines/">catalog.pcc.edu/handbook/g301-gradingguidelines</url>.
    </p>
  </introduction>

  <paragraphs>
    <title>In-class Group Work</title>
    <p>
      Most class days, you will work in small groups on a collection of exercises that go along with the lesson of the day.
      If you work on these diligently during class time with your partners,
      you will get credit for 0.5% of your final grade for each one (even if your group is not able to finish these in time).
      Sixteen of these count toward your final grade, so in total these are worth 8% of your grade.
    </p>

    <p>
      If you miss class, you may bring a <em>fully completed</em> activity to me within one week and still get the 0.5% credit.
      The online syllabus will have the exercise packets from each day for you to download
      using the <xref ref="section-calendar" text="title"/>.
      Turning these in late, they must be fully completed, not partially completed. The work must be shown, not just the answers.
    </p>
  </paragraphs>

  <paragraphs>
    <title>Online Homework</title>
    <p>
      You have online homework for each section using <webwork/>. See <xref ref="section-webwork" text="title"/> for details.
      The due date for each assignment is posted in <webwork/>. Generally when a topic is on our course calendar,
      the online homework is due the following Wednesday evening.
      You should start working on it soon after the class that works on that topic, ideally on the same day.
    </p>

    <p>
      Collectively, all the online homework is worth 10% of your final grade.
    </p>
  </paragraphs>

  <paragraphs>
    <title>Written Assignments</title>
      <p>
        In the last third of the course, your homework includes some exercises where you must write up something on paper.
        Turn these in on the days they are due.
        Each written assignment is worth 2% of your grade for a total of 6%.
        See <xref text="title" ref="section-written-assignments"/> for the specifics.
      </p>
  </paragraphs>

  <!-- <paragraphs>
    <title>Contribution to the Book</title>
    <p>The details of this assignment are at <xref text="title" ref="section-contributions"/>. You will write some content that could be added to our textbook. This assignment is worth <quantity><mag>6</mag><unit base="percent"/></quantity> of your final grade.</p>
  </paragraphs> -->

  <paragraphs>
    <title>Exams</title>
    <p>
      Please refer to the <xref ref="section-calendar" text="title"/> for exam dates,
      and <xref text="title" ref="section-exams"/> for details about what is covered on each exam.
      Exams 1, 2, and 3 are each worth 25%, 25%, and 26%, of your grade.
    </p>
  </paragraphs>

  <paragraphs>
    <title>Optional Class Prep Assignments</title>
    <p>
      This is an opportunity to reduce the weight of the exams down to just 21%, 21%, and 22%,
      padding your grade with some work that is easy to do if you budget time for it.
      At the same time, it wil get you to engage more fully with the material and it should ultimately
      help you do better on the exams.
    </p>
    <p>
      Each class day, you could come to class having <em>already</em> watched the video lessons for the day's section.
      As you watch the videos, there are video lecture notes that you could complete.
      Bringing these notes to me on the class day counts as proof that you watch the videos and engaged with them.
      For each section, I will record that you watched the videos and took notes, which credits you with 0.5% toward your grade,
      reducing the corresponding exam weight by 0.5%.
    </p>
    <p>
      If you miss class, you may scan/photo your work and send it to me electronically before the end of the day it is due.
    </p>
    <p>
      You may find the videos and the video lecture notes on the <xref ref="section-calendar" text="title"/>.
      In class on the first day, we will discuss more how this works.
    </p>
  </paragraphs>

</section>
