<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!-- This file is part of Alex Jordan's syllabus -->

<section xml:id="grades" xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude">
  <title>Grades</title>

  <p>
    General PCC Grading Guidelines are found at
    <url href="http://catalog.pcc.edu/handbook/g301-gradingguidelines/" visual="catalog.pcc.edu/handbook/g301-gradingguidelines"/>.
  </p>

  <paragraphs>
    <title>Attendance/Engagement</title>
    <p>
      Attending class is worth 4% of your final grade. If you have a reasonable circumstance where
      you need to miss class, including being sick, tell me about it. I will ask you to do a few
      small things and then you can recover the attendance credit for that day.
    </p>
  </paragraphs>

  <paragraphs>
    <title>Online Homework</title>
    <p>
      You have online homework for each section using <webwork/>. See
      <xref ref="section-webwork" text="title"/> for details. The due date for each assignment is
      posted in <webwork/>, but it will always be Sunday evening at 10:00<pm/> for full credit.
      Usually, more than one section will be due at the same time. You should start working on these
      exercises soon after the corresponding class session.
    </p>
    <p>
      Collectively, all the online homework is worth 20% of your final grade.
    </p>
  </paragraphs>

  <paragraphs>
    <title>Lab Exercise Write-Ups</title>
    <p>
      Each week you have an assignment of exercises from the <pubtite>PCC Lab Manual</pubtite> to
      complete. See <xref ref="section-weekly-routine"/> for the options on how you can be graded
      for this. Collectively, these assignments are worth 15% of your grade.
    </p>
    <p>
      The <q>due dates</q> for these assignments are Tuesday mornings. (Either in class Monday, to
      my office on Tuesday morning, or scanned and posted in D2L by Tuesday morning.)
    </p>
    <p>
      Please note that these assignments will only be scored once. There is not an opportunity to
      improve your score once an assignment is graded. But you are welcome to bring me a draft of
      your work outside of class, where we can informally look it over together to catch any
      significant issues before you turn it in.
    </p>
    <p>
      I will be looking for a few things:
      <ul>
        <li>correctness of your responses</li>
        <li>readability, including the layout of your responses and if your responses are convincing</li>
        <li>correct use of math notation and vocabulary</li>
      </ul>
      Also your write-up should connect the questions to your answers. If it's simply a list of
      answers with no context, it is not useful to you as a study tool later. So you should either
      include each question preceding each answer, or you should have a clear system for connecting
      the questions to the answers.
    </p>
  </paragraphs>

  <paragraphs xml:id="paragraphs-exams">
    <title>Exams</title>
    <p>
      There is a final exam during finals week that is worth 25% of your grade. There are also two
      midterm exams, each worth 18% of your grade. Please see the
      <xref ref="section-calendar" text="title"/> for dates.
    </p>
    <p>
      The exams will be in-class. For each exam I will allocate an appropriate amount of time, and
      remaining time will be used for lab assignment progress.
    </p>
  </paragraphs>
  <paragraphs>
    <title>Grading Options</title>
    <p>
      Students are solely responsible for adding, dropping, or withdrawing from any class, as well
      as for selecting their desired grading option. Please review
      <url href="http://www.pcc.edu/enroll/registration/policies.html" visual="www.pcc.edu/enroll/registration/policies.html">PCC Registration Policy</url>
      for more information.
    </p>
  </paragraphs>
  <paragraphs>
    <title>Letter Grades</title>
    <p>
      Your letter grade will be assigned based on the weighted average of the items above.
    </p>
      <tabular>
        <col/>
        <col right="minor"/>
        <col/>
        <col/>
        <row header="yes">
          <cell colspan="2">Pass (P)</cell>
          <cell colspan="2">No Pass (N)</cell>
        </row>
        <row>
          <cell>90% and up</cell>
          <cell>A</cell>
          <cell>60% up to 70%</cell>
          <cell>D</cell>
        </row>
        <row>
          <cell>80% up to 90%</cell>
          <cell>B</cell>
          <cell>under 60%</cell>
          <cell>F</cell>
        </row>
        <row>
          <cell>70% up to 80%</cell>
          <cell>C</cell>
        </row>
      </tabular>
  </paragraphs>
</section>
