<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<section xml:id="section-weekly-routine">
  <title>Weekly Routine</title>
  <p>
    Typically, a week covers two sections from the textbook. We discuss one section the first class
    meeting, and the other on the second. You should read these textbook sections and watch the
    embedded videos. It is best if you do this reading and watching <em>before</em> our class
    meeting. That can make the class discussion more meaningful for you. The
    <xref ref="section-calendar" text="title"/> shows you which sections are covered which weeks.
  </p>
  <p>
    You have online homework assignments for these sections in <webwork/>. You access <webwork/>
    from our D2L course. The <webwork/> assignments are due Sunday nights at 10:00pm for full
    credit. They can still be worked on up until Tuesday nights at 10:00pm for reduced credit.
  </p>
  <p>
    We spend the second half of each class meeting working on lab exercises from the
    <pubtitle>PCC Calculus Lab Manual</pubtitle>. You have options for how this goes down:
    <ol marker="a.">
      <li>
        <p>
          Stay seated near the front of the classroom. We will talk through exercises together. I
          may call upon you to share your thoughts on each exercise. Write good, complete responses
          to each exercise.
        </p>
        <p>
          By the end of the week, we may not have completed all of the exercises. I will ask you to
          complete the remainder on your own and bring them to me no later than the following 
          Tuesday morning. (Either in class Monday, to my office on Tuesday morning, or scanned and
          posted in D2L by Tuesday morning.)
        </p>
        <p>
          You will be scored full credit for the exercises we discussed as a group. I will grade the
          rest separately Tuesday afternoon. I can't accept late work after I grade things Tuesday.
        </p>
        <p>
          If you miss a class, or have to leave early some day, then I can't manage this option for
          you and you will need to use the last option below.
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>
          You can stay in the classroom, but remove yourself to the back. You can work alone, or
          perhaps with a peer as long as you are quiet enough not to distract the main group. If you
          are stuck on some exercise or need clarification about what a question is asking, you can
          signal to me and I will come help.
        </p>
        <p>
          To earn a grade for the assignment, you must give me your complete write-up by the
          following Tuesday morning. (Either in class Monday, to my office on Tuesday morning, or
          scanned and posted in D2L by Tuesday morning.)
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>
          You can leave class at this point and write up responses to the lab questions outside of
          class.
        </p>
        <p>
          To earn a grade for the assignment, you must give me your complete write-up by the
          following Tuesday morning. (Either in class Monday, to my office on Tuesday morning, or
          scanned and posted in D2L by Tuesday morning.)
        </p>
      </li>
    </ol>
  </p>
  <p>
    <alert>In all cases,</alert> for work that you do outside of class, your peers and tutors may
    help you understand the exercises, but you may not have other people or computer tools
    effectively do the exercises for you. These lab exercises are supposed to teach you things,
    and you should view them as opportunities to learn, not as homework for a grade. Then you will
    be in great shape for our exams.
  </p>
  <p>
    Throughout the week, consider reaching out for help in the following ways:
    <ul>
      <li>
        <p>the <q>Ask a Question</q> Discussion area in D2L</p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>
          contacting people from the class (if you don't have contact info, try using Connect,
          Classlist, in our D2L course)
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>free tutoring from PCC at
          <url href="https://pcc.edu/tutoring" visual="pcc.edu/tutoring"/></p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>contacting me in office hours or over email</p>
      </li>
    </ul>
  </p>
</section>
