<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<section xml:id="section-exams">
  <title>Exams</title>
  <p>
    We will have four required exams in this course. The first three are chapter exams, covering
    (respectively) chapters 1, 2, and 3. The final exam will cover all of chapters 1<ndash/>4.
    <dl>
      <li>
        <title>Chapter 1 Exam</title>
        <p>
          Wednesday 10/18
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <title>Chapter 2 Exam</title>
        <p>
          Monday 11/6
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <title>Chapter 3 Exam</title>
        <p>
          Monday 11/27
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <title>Final Exam</title>
        <p>
          Monday 12/11
        </p>
      </li>
    </dl>
    For the chapter exams, we will start class that day with a review activity, typically for about
    one hour. Then the exam will take place. I write exams designed to take some students only 50%
    of the allotted time, and I would never want you to have a low score on an exam simply because
    there was not enough time.
  </p>
  <p>
    The final exam will use our full two-hour time slot, and not be immediately preceded by a review
    session.
  </p>
  <paragraphs>
    <title>Alternatives</title>
    <p>
      If you cannot participate in an exam at its usual time or place, there are some alternatives.
      However, please note that there are no exceptions to having to take the exams with a proctor.
      If you need to explore the alternatives below, please contact me as soon as possible to begin
      discussing your options. The alternatives include:
      <ul>
        <!-- <li>
          <p>
            You identify a proctoring institution (such as another college) that is closer to where
            you live. You will be responsible for making proctoring appointments with them two weeks
            in advance of the exam dates. I will provide you with a form<fn>This form is linked from
            our D2L course at the bottom of the Content menu.</fn> that you complete with the
            assistance of that institution's testing center. You may take an exam a few days earlier
            than the dates listed above, but not later.
          </p>
        </li> -->
        <li>
          <p>
            You have an AEDR accommodation for extended time or a private working area. Then you
            will work with PCC AEDR at least one week in advance to schedule appointments for these
            exams. These might be in-person or remotely proctored, as is appropriate for your needs.
            You may take an exam a few days earlier than the dates listed above, but not later.
          </p>
        </li>
        <li>
          <p>
            If you have a scheduling conflict, you can make an appointment with a PCC testing center
            for a virtually proctored exam. Email <email>testing.remote@pcc.edu</email> to arrange
            an appointment. Once it is scheduled, <alert>contact me to tell me about your
            appointment.</alert>
          </p>
        </li>
        <!-- <li>
          <p>
            If you simply prefer to take your exams in person, you can make an appointment with a
            PCC testing center for an in-person proctored exam. Email
            <email>testing.remote@pcc.edu</email> to arrange an appointment. Once it is scheduled,
            <alert>contact me to tell me about your appointment.</alert>
          </p>
        </li> -->
      </ul>
      You may contact me if you have some situation that is not covered here and you would like to
      ask about it.
    </p>
  </paragraphs>
  <!-- <p>
    By registering for this course, you agree to all of the above. By default, you will take an exam
    using remote proctoring over Zoom at the scheduled time. Or you will plan at least one week in
    advance for one of the alternative arrangements.
  </p> -->
  <p>
    The chapter exams are each worth 11% of your final grade, and the final exam is worth 15% of
    your final grade.
  </p>
</section>
