<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<section xml:id="grades">
  <title>Grades</title>
  <p>
    General PCC Grading Guidelines are found at
    <url href="http://catalog.pcc.edu/handbook/g301-gradingguidelines/" visual="catalog.pcc.edu/handbook/g301-gradingguidelines"/>.
  </p>
  <paragraphs>
    <title>Video Lecture Notes (4%)</title>
    <p>
      Taking notes during the lectures helps students understand and retain information. Each
      section has lecture notes that accompany YouTube videos. Print these lecture note outlines and
      fill them in as you watch the videos. (Or annotate a PDF digitally.) Post them to the
      appropriate place in D2L each week. The video lecture note files are available in D2L, from
      the <q>Quick Reference</q> navbar item, in <q>Downloads</q>.
    </p>
  </paragraphs>
  <paragraphs>
    <title>Runestone Homework (24%)</title>
    <p>
      You have online homework for each section using Runestone Academy. See
      <xref ref="section-runestone"/> for details. The due date for each assignment is
      Sunday after we covered it in class. Usually, more than one section will be due at the same
      time. You should start working on a homework assignment soon after the class that is
      associated with that section of the book. Always read the textbook section, watch the
      video lectures, and complete the video lecture notes before beginning the Runestone exercises.
    </p>
  </paragraphs>
  <paragraphs>
    <title>Worksheets/Activities (24%)</title>
    <p>
      Most class sessions there is a worksheet or activity to complete and turn in. You will work
      together and with me to complete these activities. You will get my feedback on your math
      writing skills. If you miss a class or don't complete something during our class time, you can
      still complete the asignment outside of class and turn it in using D2L.
    </p>
  </paragraphs>
  <paragraphs>
    <title>Exams (11% + 11% + 11% + 15%)</title>
    <p>
      There are chapter exams and a final exam. Each exam is proctored. Most students will take each
      exam during one of our class sessions. See <xref ref="section-exams"/> for possible
      alternative arrangements.
    </p>
  </paragraphs>
  <paragraphs>
    <title>Grading Options</title>
    <p>
      Students are solely responsible for adding, dropping, or withdrawing from any class, as well
      as for selecting their desired grading option. Please review
      <url href="http://www.pcc.edu/enroll/registration/policies.html" visual="www.pcc.edu/enroll/registration/policies.html">PCC Registration Policy</url>
      for more information.
    </p>
  </paragraphs>
  <paragraphs>
    <title>Letter Grades</title>
    <p>
      Your letter grade will be assigned based on the weighted average of the items above.
    </p>
      <tabular>
        <col/>
        <col right="minor"/>
        <col/>
        <col/>
        <row header="yes">
          <cell colspan="2">Pass (P)</cell>
          <cell colspan="2">No Pass (N)</cell>
        </row>
        <row>
          <cell>90% and up</cell>
          <cell>A</cell>
          <cell>60% up to 70%</cell>
          <cell>D</cell>
        </row>
        <row>
          <cell>80% up to 90%</cell>
          <cell>B</cell>
          <cell>under 60%</cell>
          <cell>F</cell>
        </row>
        <row>
          <cell>70% up to 80%</cell>
          <cell>C</cell>
        </row>
      </tabular>
  </paragraphs>
</section>
