<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<section xml:id="section-weekly-routine">
  <title>Weekly Routine</title>
  <p>
    This course has a <q>flipped</q> design. That means that I rely on you to watch some lessons and
    do some reading <em>before</em> coming to class, not after. Then we can spend class time more
    productively. You will learn more, remember it longer, and enjoy our time in the classroom more
    this way. However <alert>it only works well if you make plans for watching the videos and doing
    the reading before class</alert>.
  </p>
  <p>
    Sometime before a given class that covers certain sections, you should:
    <ol>
      <li>watch the video lessons we provide for those sections</li>
      <li>take notes as you watch them, using the video lecture note outlines we provide</li>
      <li>read those textbook sections and complete the interactive <q>Checkpoint</q> items as you
      go</li>
    </ol>
    For each class, this will take about 3 hours of your time. So it takes around 6 hours per week.
    The reward will be more interesting things to do during class, and ultimately less homework for
    you.
  </p>
  <p>
    Our class time takes 5 hours of your time each week. Beyond this, you have up to 5 hours of
    homework each week. In total that is up to 16 hours of your time each week, which is appropriate
    for this 4-credit course.
  </p>
  <p>
    You have two forms of homework to practice the material:
    <ul>
      <li>
        <p>
          Online homework in Runestone Academy that is tied to the textbook. This includes the
          Checkpoint exercises, the Reading Questions, and some of the exercises at the end of each
          section.
        </p>
      </li>
      <li>
        <p>
          In class we do worksheets and group activities. If you complete them in class, great.
          However you may need more time outside of class to complete some of these. Or you might
          miss class. These worksheets and activities are also part of your course grade. They help
          you learn and practice math, but <em>also</em> help us work together on your math writing
          skills.
        </p>
      </li>
    </ul>
    These assignments (Runestone and the previous week's in-class activities) are <q>due</q> Sundays
    at 10:00 <pm/>. When needed, you can scan and post your work in D2L. If you miss a due date, you
    still have two weeks to catch up without any effect on your grade. But this two-week grace
    period shortens right before a test. For example our chapter 1 exam is on a Monday, and all
    chapter 1 assignments have a hard close date the day before that exam.
  </p>
</section>
